When I say people, I mean kids.
There are a bunch of kids outside my window so it's been raining a lot in Denmark the last couple days almost to the point of floods.
Well, very minor floods.
And for some reason these kids in front of my window, they pick up the water in the like huge pools of water and they throw it inside my window so there's been like a centimeter of water at the foot beneath my window inside.
So I just keep shooing them away you know and I finally got them out.
I had to just get rid of that before we started.
I closed the window now so they can't do it.
They're throwing water at the window now I see them but yeah.
What's up people?
It's Wednesday.
Oh man.
What's up everybody?
You got rid of the kids?
Definitely.
What's up big dog?
I hope you find your center today and have patience with the game on yourself.
This shit is hard man.
I was on my own little God run the other day and killed myself with a deadly heel that had piercing on it.
Taked over 500 damage in under a second.
Damn, that sucks man.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
That is frustrating.
I understand your pain.
I've also had my fair share of unfortunate demises.
Oh man.
Yujuri is editing.
What are you making Yujuri?
No idea does no to things exactly.
It's very unpredictable and it's about mitigating the chaos that you're being presented with.
Man, I've been having an itch to play this game again.
I've been super busy the start of this week.
I've been wanting to stream more but just couldn't find the time.
Oh man.
I'm so ready.
But you're completely right big dog.
It's all about having patience and going slow.
That's why the title of this video or this stream is called Noice but in Slow Motion because today we're gonna go slow.
That's why the stream is titled that way so I will do my best.
Thanks.
What's up everybody?
I see Vukul, Frank is here, Roy, Strangi or Strangi.
I sense time and space collapsing.
I know that feeling too.
Yo, Pikmin.
I haven't been in stream much since the move to Twitch but managed to catch your life for once.
I'm 12 antlers on YouTube.
Hey, what's up 12 antlers?
Were you the one who wrote a comment not so long ago about being confused by someone named antlers12 in the chat that wasn't you?
Or am I hallucinating right now?
Wait, wait, wait.
Antlers!
Wait, I'm so confused now.
Now antlers12 is writing.
What are the chances?
It's got to be the same person.
Are you messing with me, Pikmin?
Oh, you're making a super cut Ujiri.
That's awesome.
Darkwood, that's actually on my radar too.
A friend of mine has recommended it very highly.
Definitely a game I'm gonna play as well.
And there he is.
We have a 12 antlers and antlers 12 that can't be a coincidence.
There's no way.
You have encountered many others with antlers names?
Why?
Is that a thing?
It's got to be a reference to something.
Like 12 antlers, like 12 angry men or something.
My god.
That's crazy.
Antlers are cool.
A little weird when you think about it.
It's like a big growth just on your head.
Like what the hell?
Oh man, okay.
We're gonna do some nighting today.
There we are.
Let me also just dial down the relaxing thunder.
It's gone.
Oh wait, we have no sound.
The sound shall arrive.
Oh yeah.
Okay, now the plan today is of course, as always, to continue the old plan that was laid many moons ago.
Which is to do all this crap.
And we have the Rosetta Stone with us.
So we are armed with the ability to translate anything we might find.
And we have a cookbook.
It's not very extensive at this point, but we're getting there.
This game has so many layers and it's very difficult to peel them off.
But I'm slowly slowly getting there.
We have done some translations already.
Knowledge through gain, wisdom through sacrifice, teleport and bring the treasure here.
And we have to remember friendship or avarice.
That was located in the tower.
Could mean pheromone or gold is what I wrote.
And I still stand by that.
And then we of course have the map.
Begging to be filled out even more.
I'm so proud of this map.
I like looking at it.
I love filling it out even more.
It's such a satisfying feeling too.
But before we can do any of that, we obviously need to get a good run going.
That is the prerequisite.
Wait, why is it doing this?
Guys?
Why is it doing this?
Uh-oh.
Is something corrupted?
Has there been a patch or something?
Maybe I need to do a cloud save retrieval or something?
Oh no.
Please don't tell me everything is gone.
I haven't done anything to my computer.
I haven't reinstalled windows.
I haven't even reinstalled the game.
I have done nothing.
I did update windows.
That's all I did.
Let me try and exit and see if I can't retrieve cloud saves or something.
What the hell, man?
Hold on.
Let me see here.
Interface.
No, no.
How is that cloud?
Steam cloud is enabled.
No!
Wait, what?
Oh, hold on.
Cloud status, file conflict it says now.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
Oh, no.
Guys.
Oh, you can't see anything.
I have an option between a cloud save from the 5th of July and from today.
Remember you guys told me to turn off cloud saves in the beginning?
I think it was on July 5th.
I can choose to retrieve that or I can do the one I have right here, which is empty.
Oh, man.
Wait a minute.
What the hell?
You're not wrong, but apparently also you unlock new spells and stuff, right?
Oh, you made a manual backup a few times.
That's it.
Hold on.
I have... Oh, no.
I need to be more organized.
No, that's not it.
Wait, where would I put that?
Maybe I can find out where the executable is.
Installed files.
Guys, where is the save file located?
Because I may have just put it in the same folder and renamed it or something.
Oh, right.
The app data stuff.
That's right.
Okay.
So, hold on.
Let's see if I can find it.
What?
This is so weird.
I've never had this happen on Steam before.
Users.
No, wait.
App data.
Local low.
Nala games.
There.
Oh, there's actually a bunch.
There's save zero zero zero one zero two and all that.
Oh, wait a minute.
11 nine.
Oh, this is all from today.
Oh, today's 9 11.
They're all from today.
Wait, I did make a backup of this.
I'm pretty sure.
Nala games.
No, I would I put that.
No, no, no, no.
Oh, I may have found it.
I mean, I found it.
I have one from the 4th of August.
It's not too recent, but it's definitely more recent than the 7th of July.
Hold on.
I'm going to try and put it in.
And that's what she said.
Wait, what?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Put it here.
And then we're going to take this.
I did indeed make the backup as we said.
Thanks for reminding me.
I should probably not overwrite.
I'm just going to delete the folder and put the new one in just in case there's some kind of corruption thing.
Okay, here it is.
Let me disable the steam cloud again here.
Just to make sure it doesn't load that.
Wish me luck.
Oh, welcome to Neuter Epilogue 2 update.
How do I... Let's see.
Oh, this looks promising.
Aha!
All right.
But how many deaths do we have right here?
I...
There's definitely some stuff missing, right?
I mean, from the 6th of... was it August?
Or something?
That's kind of a while ago.
It's like a little... a little over a month ago.
But there it is.
We got it.
I'm going to take another backup after today just to be safe, man.
Oh, safe zero.
Zero is used.
The rest is not.
Yeah, yeah, Netriac.
I made a copy of the backup.
I didn't move it or cut it.
I made a copy.
Yeah.
All right.
Well, at least not all hope is lost, huh?
I don't know if we discovered anything new since then.
Oh, wait a minute.
A quick question for you guys.
Because I put this save file from an older version now, am I going to get the exact same order of seeds that I had?
In other words, am I going to experience the exact same worlds that I have experienced the last month, again?
Or is it random every time?
Well, I'm going to open.
No?
Okay, great.
I mean, it wouldn't be the end of the world.
It just would be kind of boring, I guess, if it was the same seeds.
Not that I remember them, but you know what I mean.
Hopefully nothing is wrong.
I only copied the Nala Game Save folder and everything in them.
And I did not override anything or merge anything.
I just put the original in completely.
So this should be a complete snapshot of whatever happened on the 6th of August.
Well, I guess we deleted some deaths.
But, you know, like 30% of those deaths didn't count anyway.
So, yeah, we're fine, right?
I'm actually so relieved.
I'm so glad you guys told me to make a backup back then.
I have no idea what could have caused this.
Dude, when I saw the intro, my heart sank.
I was like, Oh God, what now?
You know, I just knew something was really wrong.
Oh, there's a heart right there, too.
It's a great start.
I have a feeling it may have been in Windows Update.
Oh, you know what else I did?
No, no, no.
I also updated drivers for my graphics card, but I shouldn't do anything.
I don't see how that would affect the game.
Honestly, it's kind of hard to remember.
If someone asked you, what did you do to change the stuff on your computer in the last month?
It's a hard question to answer.
I'm going to take this.
Like, you will miss some stuff.
That's what I get for not playing this game for more than three days.
Or is it four days or something?
Okay.
Well, we know the drill by now.
Let's destroy that.
We're going to make some sick wands today and we're playing in slow motion because that is the key.
It is definitely the key.
In fact, it's the key in almost every game.
Unless there's a specific timer telling you you need to go fast.
Get the Hamises.
Been a while since we high fived one of those.
Hey, man.
We got to get the tablet.
Actually, let me get the tablet and then kill him.
Thanks.
Put it here.
My keybinds are still here.
That's awesome.
That was actually something I needed to check.
What if my keybinds weren't here either?
Maybe that could have been indicative of something.
Uh-oh.
Get up.
I missed.
That's actually not bad.
I can hit him with this.
Even though he's a fireman, he's not immune to fire.
It's just kind of funny.
There we go.
Actually, very surprising that he's not immune to fire.
Also, has the audio been changed here?
I don't think so.
I think it's standard volume.
Also, are my settings the same?
I guess it is.
Oh.
Turn off to prevent the game from connecting to Nala Games' servers.
Oh, that's probably from the daily run or whatever, right?
Steam Cloud is off.
Everything should be fine.
Okay.
I'm very anxious right now of losing my progress again.
I wonder how many deaths I have in this save.
I'm gonna guess like a month ago?
I think I'm below 100.
I think I started dying way more towards the end.
A magic missile.
That is very solid.
Thanks.
That is actually a fantastic damage dealer.
It is a limited use item, but for heavy enemies, definitely an amazing tool to have.
Let's convert this.
Man, look at all the himises.
Oh, beautiful.
Oh, you bastard.
Did you see that?
That little bugger hit me.
Okay, that works.
Nice.
Getting that extra gold?
Not bad.
Very nice.
Like, if you play slow and methodical with the tablet, you can do some damage.
Look at that.
Amazing.
It's two for the price of one.
I need to water myself a little bit.
You know, giving yourself a bit of momentum before you throw actually kind of nice with this makes it flow or fly a little faster.
We've got some toxic rock and a bunch of toxic sludge.
Mix it up.
Sweet.
I'm getting quite good at this.
Throwing the tablet here.
Oh, I'm stuck.
Wow, that somehow killed him.
Wasn't even that much velocity on that.
Still, the momentum was there.
Do you want some?
64 HP.
You know what's good about the tablet?
It also deflects projectiles in the air when it hits them.
It's a physical object.
Wait, how do I do this?
Destroy it.
Easiest solution.
He was baiting me.
He's a master at that.
Ah, guys, I'm in that fantastic state of mind right now, where I don't have any work at this moment.
And I'm just here to exist in this world playing video games.
You know, that's my purpose.
It's just such a liberating feeling.
I love it.
No, don't do that.
Wow.
He almost killed himself.
I wonder if that would have given me double gold.
Sir.
Oh, look at this.
They're hiding things from me.
I should probably use this for that.
Oh, yeah.
What are we?
Oh, sick.
Long distance cast, speed up.
Electric charge could be fun.
I'm gonna buy a lot of this.
Okay, let's focus on killing this guy first.
One thing at a time.
Don't get overexcited.
We should really turn this into water.
I'm buying it all.
I think all of these are handy.
This one even gives some damage, right?
Yeah, eight damage is pretty good.
Nothing to be scoffed at.
Somehow he survived.
I got to get back into the Neuter lifestyle.
It's been a while.
Make a little shortcut there for later.
Let's go to the left
and see what trouble we can get into.
I kind of want to find... actually, this wand is not bad.
Ah, wait, it's shuffle.
I was gonna say, I want to find a couple more wands.
Decent wands that I can put the spells I found into.
Wait, what's happening here?
Why is this so weird?
Doesn't this almost look like I need to do something here?
Like,
something's going on here.
There's two pillars on each side.
A bunch of toxic sludge.
Maybe not.
I'm probably overthinking this.
But it's possible.
I feel like if there's a puzzle type situation, it's usually kind of obvious.
And that wasn't super obvious to me.
Or maybe I'm just saying that and it's not obvious.
And I miss most of them.
Oh my god, he actually hit me quite a lot.
I think it's maybe time to get out.
We got a lot of gold.
Oh, actually, we don't.
We spend it all.
Ugh.
Okay, I want to stay a little bit longer.
Not too long, though.
How did you hit me, asshole?
I was really trying not to get hit.
And yet you do it anyway.
If I can find a teleport in the holy mountain, that would be the dream right now, given
the long path.
Super careful, I swear.
I swear that mostly to myself.
Oh,
show me that gold.
A little bit of gold.
Just get rid of the hazards and the hazard down there as well.
Yep.
Let's get rid of it.
Water myself to be safe.
Let's go.
He died?
Yep.
That was a little bit sketchy.
Nice.
Someone's down there.
I want to get to 300 gold or something.
That would be the ideal amount.
This guy here is going to be troublesome, I think.
Oh, very nice.
Very nice.
Got him.
Okay, I think that's about it.
Now we leave.
280.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
And we got some sick spells already.
Another long distance cast, but no teleport.
What's that one?
Sea of water.
Hmm.
Ooh, I like this.
Toxic immunity.
That's a solid start.
Hell yeah.
Very nice.
Okay.
And spirit bolt with timer.
I like that one.
I like this one.
I like... what else do I like?
Maybe that's all I like for now.
Okay, we're building once again.
Let's see if we can make something happen.
I'm thinking this wand, or actually this wand.
We want to put something on the timer, for sure.
The question is what?
Unfortunately, we do not have a no shuffle wand with more than three slots.
Because I want to do a triple scatter on the spitter bolt with timer.
So that is not happening, unfortunately.
So maybe that's not in the cards for now.
But I can put something at the end.
A single one, I guess.
Something... oh, wait a minute.
We can do something like this.
We can do something good here, actually.
This should be pretty good.
Add eight damage to this.
Oh, that's not bad at all.
That's actually sick.
Solid.
How fast is it?
It's kind of slow, I guess.
Oh, notice how?
Because it's on a timer.
If I don't hit anything, it's gonna just shoot off in a horizontal pattern.
That's cool.
I like that for now.
Long distance.
Oh, I also have this one.
Return.
After a period of time, you'll be returned to where you cast the spell.
Oh, wait.
Wait a minute.
I return here?
Yes!
I never realized this!
That's fucking huge.
I thought it was where my character was, but it's not obviously.
It's a projectile!
It was cast from!
Oh my god.
Okay, that's great.
I'm loving it already.
This is fantastic.
I like this wand.
That'll be enough for now, for what I haven't planned here.
I'm gonna make a throwaway wand.
I don't want shuffle.
Actually, I'm just gonna put it on this, because we're not gonna use a shuffle single slot wand for anything.
That sucks.
I'm just gonna shoot this off five times at someone unfortunate.
Okay, um, should I be buying anything else here?
Let me think.
Sea of water could be interesting.
I do like that.
This is sort of digging, let's not forget.
And this is actually a potential steward killer.
Oh, with the long distance?
Yo, we have the tools to make something great!
Not that we need to kill steward right now, because we have the teleport.
But it's there.
Wait, why is this one red?
Oh my god, never mind.
It's just been a while since I've played Noita.
Okay, it will still do the dig.
That's better.
This is gonna be a throwaway.
This is a throwaway.
I honestly don't want the pollen in the long run, I don't think.
I'm not the biggest fan of that.
Also, I need more water.
More water for me.
Fill it up.
Okay.
Also, cheers, everybody.
Hope you're having a great Wednesday so far.
I'm just so happy I managed to sort of recover the save file.
I was in shambles, guys.
Oh wait, what now?
I shot it twice.
Oh!
Dude.
Return.
I've been sleeping on it.
Let's see here.
That is a decent want for digging.
At least way better than this one.
I mean, if I hit them with this, it's gonna hurt.
This is awesome.
I can't believe it.
We have found another method to circumvent Stuart.
It's actually awesome.
Well, not just Stuart, but also just the collapsing of the holy mountain.
It's so nice.
Okay, so we have this one now.
Let's put this on that.
I like that more in the long run, I think.
Not as fast, but...
Actually, the one is not bad in general here.
This is a decent looking want.
Too bad it only has two slots.
Maybe just put this on here for now, then.
No, no, no, no.
Just put the digging on.
Although...
I mean, for the digging I'm gonna do, I feel like this is actually better.
Yeah, and then do this, and we throw this one away.
The explosive box.
I don't know about... Actually, hold on.
This is also a potential Stuart killer, remember?
Explosive box is everywhere.
We summon him, he arrives, boom!
His life's over.
Okay, let's explore... Hold on.
To the right first.
I got a little bit lucky there.
I'm gonna admit that.
Oh, oh wait, these can't hit me.
They're fine.
Oh my goodness.
This guy won't die.
Kind of hard to hit with it.
As soon as I find a one with more slots on it, it's gonna be way better.
I can put speed up on it as well and make it do way more damage and make it shoot faster.
It's just gonna be great.
Is there a den mother here somewhere?
There's an awful lot of you purple folk.
Slimy folk.
Gooey folk.
Is that that rat?
I think it is.
Next.
Ah!
Damn fire.
At least I'm immune to toxic.
That's huge.
There is a den mother.
I mean, I'm doing respectable damage here.
This is totally acceptable.
Oh, someone was trying to dig here?
What the hell is this?
Now that's what I'm talking about.
Although the recharge time is terrible, it does have awesome spells on it.
The dig is back boys.
We're gonna be digging.
Also, is this gonna be enough to get through here?
Let's see.
No, but what if I...
So I guess I can't spawn in the brickwork.
Ah!
Never mind!
It sort of worked.
I was close enough.
Very neat.
Okay, um, let's see here.
It's a no shuffle one, but it has four seconds recharge.
That is unbelievably bad.
I don't need all of these, I don't think.
Three spells per cast.
And honestly a very mediocre one in general.
It has a lot of slots and that's about the only thing it has going for it.
I will be...
keeping it, but throwing it away at the first opportunity.
So the digging.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
I think I like just... yeah, I like that.
This is my digging wand.
I like it more than the other.
I probably can't do that.
I think it's easier to just go over here.
Dude, another thing I'm gonna try with the return...
is before I go through a portal, just cast it.
So I can get back, you know, maybe quickly heal up, go back, or grab spells, go back.
Imagine if you find the spell that also extends the duration.
You can really give yourself some time.
Wow, I hit that projectile mid-air.
Oh, I really need a better wand though.
I'm getting hit a lot here because I just don't have the firepower to deal with people properly.
Ooh, nice.
A heart.
I shall gladly pick it up.
Three spells per cast.
Actually, not a bad wand.
Oh, but two seconds recharge time.
Shit.
That's bad.
I guess I'll take it over this.
Better than nothing.
That is one is very hard to make work.
Shit.
I just get that shot off.
Nice.
Oh, that was beautiful.
So much fire.
Imagine if I find fire resistance as well.
Having both fire and toxic resistance would be stellar.
Do we have a nest here or something?
Oh, one of them hit me.
Incredible.
Come on.
I'm in maximum focus mode.
I'm a sweaty gamer right now.
There's something in there.
Oh, wait!
No, wrong spell.
Shit.
Okay, nothing happened.
Good.
This is very awkward to dig with when you don't have a good place to stand.
That works.
Okay, that wasn't very exciting.
I was hoping for a heart or something.
Ah, we can get through here.
Let's try not to get hit by the spell here.
I've had many such issues in the past.
Oh, we've got things up here as well.
Oh, okay, guys.
They had a trap set up.
Okay, that's the edge.
All right.
Water this.
If I can find one more heart, I would be so happy.
I feel like the amount of hearts you find is...
I don't know, it's a good indicator for me.
At least in my case, if I'm gonna get a good run or not.
Later on.
If you get into the...
the cycle of always leaving a level...
super early without finding the gold or the hearts, it always spirals out of control.
And so far it's looking good.
Okay.
We gotta go to, uh...
the fungal caverns.
In fact, let's head there now before we get too low HP.
That place is a death trap.
Anything down here?
Okay.
Shit!
Whoa!
Okay.
That was a mistake.
I know I'm immune to this, but I'm still doing it out of habit.
It's just...
That's something I can't get rid of.
You gotta get rid of the toxic.
It's just...
It's a rule.
Oh!
Wow.
Okay, I think that's our cue to leave.
We're simply too low HP now.
Like, anything in the fungal cavern is gonna kill me now.
Especially if there's also people teleporting me everywhere.
It's just... it's no good.
But let me just kill this guy and get a little bit of money.
Ah, you fucking asshole.
Almost got me.
Oh, you know what I'm gonna do now?
We're gonna try the teleport thing.
Um, uh, probably not here, because I'm afraid of the lava.
I'm going to the next.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna...
This is gonna work, right?
Oh, sick!
It is a bit risky though, because if I start to explore here now, I lose HP and then go back.
I don't know, man.
Then we don't have any healing for the next area.
It can become bad.
Let's say if we lose more than...
I don't know.
If we are at...
Less than 75% HP, then we're gonna leave.
That seems reasonable.
No questions asked.
We leave.
No matter what.
No greediness.
Fully disciplined.
How do I get in there?
Probably going this way.
What's up there?
Fair- Ooh!
I like that.
Close.
Don't break the thingy.
Wait, what?
I'm stuck.
Got it!
Pheromone is important later on.
Oh, we gotta get high as well.
But I think I'm gonna delay doing that experiment until later in a run.
You know, just...
Not when I'm trying to- holy shit, man.
Everything's on fire.
Not when I'm just trying to survive here and find something to work with.
Oh my god, I didn't even see you.
I was burning alive.
Hello!
I do feel like we need a better wand if we are to go in there.
There's something a little bit faster.
There's gotta be a wand here somewhere.
Or we just go there and find the- because there's wands in there, right?
Quickly grab and leave again.
Oh, nice.
Whoa, sick!
Super glad I didn't leave yet.
What's down here?
Wait, what?
Ah, here we go.
Hold on, I gotta sneeze.
Now I'm ready.
Fungal caverns.
And already things are looking grim.
Electricity.
And we've got a mage.
What do you do, sir?
Does he make me blind?
Is that him?
I can't even reach him with this.
This is not good.
This man does not die.
Got him.
Whoa!
I'm so scared of that ball.
I don't know what's in it.
I knew it was an Ukuskivi.
Always
Ukuskivi.
Oh, this guy has no chill.
Yeah, my wand is definitely not very great.
I just gotta find one wand in here.
There's bound to be something really good.
And I haven't lost more than 75% of my HP.
Remember, this loss right here is from picking up a heart.
I did not lose that, so it doesn't count.
That's what I say.
Oh, what is that?
That's a mage shot.
Yep.
I think it's the teleporter.
He pleads teleportation.
Oh, that was close.
Uh, sir?
Oh.
These things are gonna be hell.
Yeah, look at his teleportation.
Unstable teleportation in that one.
What the hell is... Why... Are these guys teleporting or what's happening?
That's so weird.
Look at this.
The way they're... Oh, they're jumping back.
It just looks very...
This is the most scuffed wand for being here.
Another Ukuskivi.
Wow, he died.
I'm greedy.
I'm okay.
Okay.
It paid off.
I need to, uh...
Kill him!
Yep, yep, yep, yep, yep, yep.
And then we gotta do something like that.
I kind of need to pick that up because I'm scared it will get into the hands of the wrong person.
Nice.
That works.
And we gotta wand.
Always casts Matter Eater.
That sounds pretty cool.
I like it.
But I'm kind of scared of it.
I forgot exactly how that works.
I gotta experiment, but in a safe spot.
Come here.
Really awkward to have the levitation potion on, actually.
I can't hit him.
There we go.
Have these guys always done that where they go back like that?
That seems super weird.
Like, look at this.
It's weird as hell.
Somehow that hit him.
I'm impressed.
Let me also quickly take a look.
Four spells per cast and a high recharge.
Not great.
It's not what I'm looking for.
I just need something basic, man.
It doesn't have to be incredible.
Just give me something that doesn't straight up suck, you know?
That's all I ask.
That's all I ask, man.
Oh, shit.
My goodness.
This one really does have very little damage, doesn't it?
There's not a lot.
Okay.
There we go.
Why am I getting that music as if I'm high?
I'm not high.
I'm totally not high.
That guy was actually kind of interesting.
He didn't shoot me immediately.
Is he some kind of friendo?
Kind of want to try and pheromone it next time to see what happens.
Okay, here we are at this spot.
This is the secret area or the area with secrets.
There we go.
Getting decent money too here.
It's not bad.
Gunpowder potion.
I don't want that.
Gotcha.
Let's see.
That's looking a little better.
But not fantastic.
It's still quite a high recharge time.
Not liking it.
I can get in there, by the way.
I can get in anywhere.
One second recharge.
No, thank you.
Here
we go.
This is the one.
Okay, that's not bad.
That's better than this one.
Sort of.
Oh, and there's a sparkle with trigger on.
That's also very nice.
Uh, let me quickly check exactly what this one does.
Matter eater.
Oh!
What?
Oh, I thought it was the earthquake one.
Never mind.
Wait, wait, wait.
I thought it was the one that shook everything.
Dude, this is nuts.
Okay, I'm definitely keeping this one.
That's crazy.
What the hell?
I wonder if that goes through everything.
Let's do absolutely everything.
Let's see here.
There's metal here, if that works.
It's a black hole in projectile form.
What?
Dude, we don't need this anymore.
We don't need a plasma cutter.
We also have more plasma cutters at home.
Makes me think of that meme now.
Plasma cutters at home.
Ah, what the hell, man?
This is not my digging wand.
That's crazy.
That is so good.
Does it do... Oh, it goes through enemies.
No, wait.
He's a friend.
Wait, is that not gold?
No, it's a Kiva skeevie.
Okay.
Spiral arc and a bunch of missiles.
I do not think so.
I'm okay.
The wand wasn't that great either.
Like, how absurd is this?
Look at this.
The digging is out of this world.
Now we're talking.
That's what I want.
But I can't rea...
I need to take it with wands.
First, we gotta deal with these guys.
My friend is helping me.
Thanks, dude.
Is he gonna turn on me at some point when that runs out?
Critical plus is cool.
This wand is not bad at all.
It's actually a decent wand.
Look at this, also a high mana charge speed.
I think I'm gonna replace it with this and come back for the spark bolt.
With trigger.
Let's go back to the cave.
Oh, wait a minute.
I can just do this stuff.
Oh, it bounces off and starts digging that way then.
That's very interesting behavior.
Oh, shit.
Ah, yeah, there we go.
Odd fire bolts.
This one is also not the worst, but it is kind of the worst.
We got a mage!
Get him, buddy!
Get him!
Did he just get hit by the mage bolt and then he started turning on me?
Like, what just happened there?
Got him.
Dude, this one is insane.
Matter eater.
Oh, no, we have a wand here.
That's not looking great, is it, guys?
That's...
Ah!
Oh, fuck!
Shit!
I didn't think that would hit me there!
What the hell?
Oh, it's like random where the electricity spreads look.
Sometimes it goes up here, sometimes it doesn't.
Okay, I'm not taking that wand.
That's too scary.
Nope.
Please.
I don't have the range to deal with them.
There we go.
Oh, shit.
Let's just water myself.
Very nice.
Let's go.
I gotta be careful not to anger Stuart now.
I have the capability of doing that.
Oh, it even allows me to...
Wait, does it?
Does it actually black hole the...
Oh, I think it does black hole the items.
The gold disappears.
It eats it.
The matter eater.
It eats the matter.
Okay, I thought maybe it would be a black hole and still allow me to get the gold, you know?
But I'm still happy.
I'm not disappointed.
This is still great.
Take me home.
Okay.
Now, keep this, keep that.
The rest is very bad.
There we go.
Now, on this wand...
Ideally, I want the spark bolt with trigger here instead, because then this won't run out, you know, and explode in the midair.
Which I hate.
But for now, we can do this.
Let's put a triple.
It does cost one mana.
This costs two mana.
Wait, why does that cost two mana?
Oh, it...
reduces spread too.
Oh, weird.
I'm gonna put this here and we're gonna put some speed on front.
Much better.
And maybe put some crit inside of there.
We can put two more projectiles.
What should we put as the last one?
So, we're limited by recharge time?
That reduces recharge time.
And it doesn't matter if it's in here.
Amazing.
Can we make it even better?
Hold on, eight damage, five damage.
Maybe we don't want these.
Hold on a second.
Five mana drain.
Whoa!
Oh, but these also do slice damage.
I see.
These actually reduce cast delay as well.
Not that we need it.
We're limited by recharge time here.
Maybe I'll do one of these in here then, just for the...
just for the lulz, you know?
What else should I put in there?
I think we're fine.
We can't put anything else.
Okay.
Uh, next up.
So, that's our main wand now.
This is still fine.
The rest is still fine.
Now we leave.
Boop!
Nice.
Ah!
Oh!
Whoa!
Boop!
We're not done.
What up?
I forgot my Matter Eater.
I was just about to dig and I was like, wait a minute.
Something ain't right.
What should we use?
Probably just this.
Oh, maybe something that doesn't bounce.
I think we had the Ispiter bolt on it before, right?
Uh, maybe that's what we have to do actually.
Although I wonder.
Ooh, hold on a second.
I wonder.
What if we do... Okay, I'm just gonna try something crazy.
Oh wait, this is limited.
Never mind.
It's limited.
Uh, get rid of the long distance again.
I think I like having the Spitter bolts in here.
It's fine.
We just need a bunch of spells here.
That's the only limitation.
Need a bunch of them.
Get one more.
The Poland?
I don't know about the Poland.
I think we're fine now.
Uh, okay, let's go.
I really want to find a proper teleport.
Now we can do it.
But look at that.
The digging.
Why is it so... Oh, it's four spells per cast.
I understand now.
Shit.
I see.
That guy just died.
And I did it.
It was me.
I killed him.
Oh, yeah, I'm a killer.
I mean, I'm not a killer, but don't push me.
You know what I'm saying?
There we go.
A chainsaw!
And a decent wand.
Look at the wand here!
Yo!
Why am I going to fungal caverns when all I need is right here?
Go here.
I'm doing a lot of backtracking here, but I feel like that's what you have to do when you're playing this game in slow motion.
Okay, now let's see.
Oh, but we are losing a lot of slots.
But we will be shooting much faster.
Let's not forget that part.
But this does reduce recharge time.
Hold on a second.
Wow, that adds castellae.
Okay, I like that.
But hold on, can we make it even better?
Let's think.
Oh, actually.
Having the recharge be so big is essentially like having an ad mana on here, which is kind of huge.
You know.
I think I like the setup here, but can we make it... I'm just gonna experiment a bit with moving this around, because sometimes unexpected things happen.
Yeah, we definitely want the speed on the spitter bolt.
And let's see here.
So...
This is the first projectile.
Which will unleash a triple scatter spell on impact, or after time it runs out.
Which then shoots this entire thing right here.
Critical plus, heavy spread, a spitter bolt, and a chainsaw.
That is all contained in there.
I'm trying to figure out if I can do a double dip.
A double dippy do.
Here.
But I think I need more slots for it.
So let's say I had a quadruple here.
And I put the...
Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on.
I can also do this.
Like that, maybe.
Let's see.
Okay, it's not quite the same.
It's actually worse, because it shoots the chainsaw on the front.
So the damage is not being applied.
Yeah, we hate that.
This is way better.
And it's good.
It's a good wand.
I'm liking.
I'm a liker.
Ooh, wait a minute.
I just had an idea.
What if we were to do something naughty here?
How naughty is this?
I'm testing not here, but outside.
I'm scared.
Oh!
Okay.
Oh my god.
Fuck me.
I was hoping it would just be...
Okay, so here's my thought process behind why I did what I just did, okay?
Because I feel like I need to explain myself.
The summon explosive box is kind of a huge projectile, okay?
In size.
Physical dimensions.
So I was thinking if I can shoot that, it will carve out a huge black hole-sized hole where it ends up falling.
So I thought, oh, I could just throw these everywhere and it will dig a large hole for me.
Because it converts everything, it consumes the matter, right?
But yeah, it says, gee, oh my god.
I'm a 2 HP.
Holy shit.
I don't even know if I can survive to get to the next portal.
This is getting a little bit sketchy.
Yikes.
Oh no, I already healed at the next...
Oh no.
Oh.
It may actually be over.
I need to get through two areas now.
Let me see if I have left anything behind.
You know what?
I'm gonna have a...
emergency sea of water that I will put if I'm on fire.
I just instantly switch the fort and it just, you know?
There it is.
Okay, let's go.
Very careful now.
I've already carved a path to the portal.
I just need to retrace my steps.
Oh.
I'll take that.
Imagine if there was health in here or like a healing.
Wouldn't that be incredible?
The good news is we can dig.
I'm just gonna dig.
Oh wait, I fucked up putting this here.
I think.
Oh!
Yo, look at this!
How did I do this last time?
Oh, I gotta translate what it says.
Hold on.
Uh, where's my...
switch to here?
Uh, no, no, actually.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Nope.
No, no, no, no.
There we go.
It happened.
The deadly heel is way too deadly right now.
Okay.
Unfortunately, I'm not a vampire.
Otherwise, I would have been sucking on that blood.
You don't even know.
Thanks!
Well, that was unexpected.
Uh, I guess we keep digging.
I'm so scared of actually hitting some kind of buried explosive barrel or something.
Wait, is that an enemy?
No.
I hear a portal.
It's down here.
I also do hear fire.
Just go.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
What do we got?
Unlimited spells.
Oh, that's that's so tempting.
So is this one though.
Oh, man.
Worm attractor.
I gotta go with unlimited spells.
It's too good.
I gotta do it.
Now I need to find out how not to die.
I mean, I'm gonna prepare myself here because I'm probably just gonna die.
Wait!
I actually do have another way of healing.
In the beginning.
How do I get back though?
I need to get to the cave.
How do I get back without angering Stuart?
Uh...
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Can I use this somehow?
I can't anger anybody.
If I anger Stuart, I'm dying.
100%.
Even though I may have the chance to kill him, he will kill me.
I have 2 HP.
I just can't, I can't take that shot.
Oh, man.
Is there anything I can do to get up again?
Uh...
Whoa, wait a minute.
There is actually a...
thing I can do.
We are in the frost level now.
If I go to the right, I can go up.
Remember the the huge drop?
But I still have to get through the frost level.
So there's still that.
Come on.
Oh my god.
I'm gonna die here.
I'm 100% gonna die here.
There's so many enemies!
Come on.
Come on, you fucker.
I need to go right.
But anything that hits me, I'm dead.
Hold on.
I need to lay a battle plan here.
This is...
It's not okay.
Hold on.
We need to think.
This is too good of a situation to throw away.
Can I use my... I was about to say unstable teleportation, but I actually meant to say my return.
Somehow.
What other spells do I possess?
I do have long... Oh!
Ah, fuck.
Am I gonna have to dig?
Oh wait, I have an idea.
I have an idea.
Dude, I'm so dumb.
I'm so fucking dumb.
I have an idea.
We are gonna dig.
But it's just gonna be not here.
We can we can always dig or... Oh, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Let me think.
If I...
If I dig here, Stuart is gonna appear.
No, I can't dig.
I can't dig.
It's it's gonna fuck me.
I think I just have to accept this is probably over.
I made a huge mistake, uh...
Using that wand over there.
It is what it is.
I need to kill this guy.
He will... Actually, I don't.
Let's see what's on the right side.
Like anything right now kills me.
Do I have toxic immunity?
Like any little blue, uh...
Yeah, there it is.
We're leaving.
Oh!
No, no, no, no.
Okay, we have to try and dig.
We got to try and dig.
This is just not happening.
Nope, we're digging.
We're digging.
I'm gonna dig as far away from Stuart as I can.
Just in the hopes that he's not gonna notice me and everything's gonna be fine.
Uh, okay, let's go.
Okay, go, go.
Go, go, go!
Come on, come on.
Please, no enemies.
Now I need to not die here.
Uh-oh.
Okay, okay, this is safe, I think.
Oh, man.
Uh, go left, I think.
I could dig here.
Wait, it's not right, it's left.
Because I see darkness.
Wait, there's... wait, what?
Shit, shit, shit, shit.
Go this way.
I think it's to the right.
Oh, yeah, here it is, here it is.
I am so on edge.
I don't need to be on edge, man.
This is just the start of the run.
It's like, whatever, right?
Really.
Let's see if there's any enemies hanging out here.
I think we're okay, we're okay, we're okay.
Okay, time to anger the next one.
Oh, but dude, even getting to the... to the cave is gonna be troublesome.
Oh, we know what?
We need light, actually.
We need light.
Put light on...
I think this is better.
Just so we... oh, wait, no, no, no, no, no, put it here, actually.
Yeah, better, better.
We need some lights.
So hold on, right now we are in the cold pits.
Now we go up again.
Let me go at an angle.
Here we go.
Don't get scared, don't get scared.
The tech's gonna pop now.
Don't get scared.
Come on, pop the text.
Pop it for me.
Okay, there it is.
Fuck!
I literally cannot control my fucking emotions.
Uh, oh, wait, wait, wait, the best way, I think.
We have to approach from the top.
Okay, this is the plan.
We're going... oh, no, there's an enemy.
He's dead.
I'm gonna go to the beginning, and then we're gonna approach from the top, because we can dig.
We can dig.
Everything's fine.
The digging is real.
Uh, wait, where am I right now?
Maybe this is a mistake.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Uh...
Uh, go back.
We can always... okay, there's an enemy there.
I can always dig, uh, anywhere, so to be safe, right?
I'm just gonna dig like this, I think.
But hold on, there's an enemy in there.
Almost missed you.
Who's up there?
Oh!
No, we're going back up.
Just do it.
Just get me to the top.
Okay, that's kind of promising.
Now I just need to remember exactly where...
Hold on.
Let's see here.
Hopefully I can trust my own map here.
According to my map, it is...
kind of... oh yeah, I know this.
It's sort of left to the roots, right?
So I go through tree, down.
It's the tree.
Tree, tree, tree, tree, tree.
Let's be careful.
Up here, sometimes there's enemies up here.
And they appear randomly.
I don't understand that, actually, but sometimes they do.
I gotta get to the roots.
Actually, these are the roots.
Dude, the Matter Eater is fantastic.
When we can upgrade this one and make it fast... shoot faster, it's gonna be wild.
It cuts through anything.
Oh, fuck, the music is playing.
I was like just being like, huh, that's nice music.
And then I noticed, wait a minute, this is not the music that should play right now.
I'm so sorry, guys.
It failed.
I was too focused.
I was too excited.
It wasn't that long.
It's okay.
We made it.
Oh, that's at the edge.
Okay, that's not the healing.
Uh, hold on.
That's a bit scary.
Oh, shit.
Where is it though?
Hold on a second.
Need to find out exactly where it is.
Sit down there.
I just don't want to encounter enemies.
Got it.
Yes, baby!
We are back.
We freaking did it.
That's huge.
Oh, what a scare.
Fucking crisis management here.
Incredible.
Just incredible.
All right.
Very nice.
I feel so much better.
I feel like just exploring the rest of this place.
Now we got to go to the frosty cave.
The frozen... I forgot the name.
Something.
Uh,
where is Stuart?
Hello?
Wait, did I not dig here just before?
What's happening?
Hello?
Huh.
Maybe he wandered off somewhere.
That's probably what happened.
He's somewhere down here.
I need to be ready.
All right, Stuart.
I'm ready to face you.
I do have a great wand, actually.
I can fuck him up, probably.
Actually, take me back real fast.
I'm gonna replace my light with the critical plus.
Oh, actually, no, no, no.
I'm gonna go to fungal caverns now and I'm gonna grab the spark bolt with trigger.
That's what I'm gonna do.
And now, oh, let's just take a moment, okay?
Because look at this.
We have deadly heal now.
That's huge.
Get rid of that.
Ground to sand.
Makes any hard solid materials within a projectile's range turn into sand.
And this is now infinite.
I believe this one had a limit before I picked up unlimited spells.
Firebolt is also unlimited now.
Cost 50 mana, though.
Maybe this is worth it putting here.
Although it does shoot, well, fireballs.
So that can hurt me, right?
No?
Wait, what?
What?
No way!
I'm immune?
Huh!
Oh, that's awesome.
Well, in that case, I'm gonna put two of them there and then remove the light.
Let's do this.
Something like that.
That is gonna slap.
I mean, it is gonna set things on fire.
Let's not forget that and that can hurt me.
So yeah.
Okay.
Although I do, I wonder if it's better to have this one on it.
I mean, that is 33 damage and 47 explosive damage.
But then again, critting with that is gonna dramatically increase the damage.
But it is a bit RNG, right?
Let's put this on here.
Right, we're not limited by cast delay.
It's the other one.
So let's put it back.
I really do like how that feels.
Let's put a light on here.
That's gonna make it shoot much faster now.
Actually, it shoots two rounds before the recharge timer activates now.
And it does so because...
because it shoots four spells per cast.
One, two, three, four.
That's the first badge, right?
The next one is one, two.
But this one is a modifier and it doesn't have anything here.
So it goes here.
So that's why it shoots too fast.
And then the recharge timer activates.
Much more effective, actually.
Maybe I'll do a spark bolt.
And spark bolt is too narrow to dig with, right?
Wouldn't be optimal here.
So now we have a healing method.
Let's see if we can't make that even better.
I can probably do that in water.
That's how that works.
Let me take the bigger water.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
We need something so I can hit myself with it.
We need bloodlust.
Or something equivalent first.
So basically this is useless right now, unfortunately.
Yeah.
Okay.
Also, quantum split is kind of interesting.
I don't think I quite understand the way that works.
And why is Stuart not here?
That's... I don't understand.
Wait, did I just do this digging?
Oh my god, I didn't even notice.
I guess Stuart doesn't mind?
Stuart?
He must be off somewhere.
He's already spawned.
He's roaming somewhere in the coal pits.
Okay, let's go grab that spark bolt with trigger.
Wow, the recoil is significant now that I have the fire bolts.
This thing is going to slap now.
Like this one right here is going to hurt.
When that hits something, it'll die.
Time to get some revenge on the fungal caverns.
Hopefully find some more hearts as well.
And we're going to get high.
So I'm going to try and get high on the platform this time.
That was the plan.
But first... Oh shit!
It's one of those fuckers.
The swappers.
Bukuskivi.
Did I check that?
I think I did.
I did.
Oh yeah.
Levitatium.
That's the one I dropped.
So I think... Is it that one right there?
Or was it this one up here?
None of those.
It's that one, I think.
No, no, no.
I never checked that because it's too dangerous.
I just realized, by the way, if we find a homing and a rock, you know what's about to happen.
You know what I'm going to do.
It's going to be glorious.
Fireball orbits.
Actually a decent wand.
The stat wise, I quite like that.
In fact, so is this one.
Look at 810 mana charge speed.
But it is shuffle, so there's that.
I don't know where that wand is that I left.
Maybe it's more to the west, actually.
Also, I am going to leave something behind.
I'll probably just leave that one behind for now and come back for it.
The circium.
Oh, we got a mage.
Uh oh.
No, wait, that's not a mage.
I have to remember, I basically have a black hole right now.
Insane spell.
Okay, that's the one I already checked.
I think it's maybe that one.
No,
nope.
It's got to be close.
Although, you know, I do kind of like the Spitterball with timer when I have the speed up.
It is a higher area projectile.
It's easier to hit enemies with it.
You know, so there's that.
I think it's that one.
There it is.
I'm taking it.
Because if I do that, that means I can give up the speed up and put something else there instead.
It's actually all the way at the top.
Let's not forget that.
I can dig anywhere.
I have to get used to this.
Wait, this is not doing as much damage as I thought it would.
Enemies are not instant dying.
I feel like that was a lot of damage.
I guess I'll just dig through this stuff.
Stuart is already angered, obviously.
So who cares?
Maybe not here.
I do want to preserve the water.
I wonder where he went.
Actually grab some water.
There we go.
Now, put this.
So how much mana is this?
10 mana.
Oh, it's actually a little bit worse.
Although it does add crit chance.
This one adds spread, which I don't like.
I can get rid of this.
And that's decent.
Now we need to speed it up a little bit.
Wait, wait, wait.
Why is that suddenly faster?
Am I limited by Castelay?
No, no, that's recharge time, no?
But I guess not.
Wait, what?
I'm so confused.
0.57 minus 0.25 minus 0.17.
I mean, maybe I am limited by Castelay.
This is definitely faster.
I mean, it's much better.
I'll take it.
I like it.
And then I'm going to leave this here, that one there, and this one can go fuck itself.
Bye-bye.
Put this here instead.
Maybe I don't like these on that wand.
Oh, wait a minute.
Should I be using a speed up on this?
One, two, three, four.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Let's do this.
One, two, three, four.
Next.
No, not really.
Hold
on, let me see the board.
That's only shooting one of them.
Okay, fine.
I'll do it like that.
That's okay.
All right, let's go grab our heals.
And then we're gonna get high.
That's the plan.
Cheers.
I really need to... I need to find a projectile that doesn't bounce.
The bouncing is annoying me.
Makes the digging difficult.
Look at this artistic dig.
Looks like brushstrokes.
I like it.
Look at that, big boy.
Thanks.
Worm pheromone, gunpowder, broken wand.
I think I may take it.
I will take that one.
And get rid of... Oh, I actually do kind of want to keep these.
I can get rid of that one, of course.
What am I talking about?
Flammable gas in there, too.
Hey, thanks.
Oh, wait, the digging is way worse now.
Oh, wait, I fucked up.
I messed up the wand.
I totally messed it up.
That guy was protected by a sliver of terrain.
This wand is fun.
Makes the whole screen shake.
That's how powerful it is.
Yeah, I definitely need to change this wand.
This digging wand is not as great as it was.
I think the energy bolt was better.
Okay, let's try and get high here.
But how do I do it so I do it on the platform?
If I had a pouch, I could bring it with me.
Maybe there's something close to it.
Where's the platform again?
Is it down here?
No.
Where was it?
I feel like it should be somewhere up to the left.
That's my general feeling on it.
Not all the way up left, but close.
What?
Ah, here it is.
Here it is.
Okay, we do have a bit of mushrooms down below.
I'm gonna eat from here and go up.
See what happens.
Let's eat somewhere here.
Okay, show me the goods.
SEMA again?
Okay, I don't think it did anything.
Unless we need to do it three times, like it said with the three eyes.
But sure, SEMA.
I like to see... Oh, wait.
Wait, what was this before?
No.
Wait a minute.
That's blood.
What changed?
Why is there SEMA everywhere?
Hold on.
What's missing?
What's missing from this picture right here?
Oh my god, there's no more mushrooms.
They're all gone.
Look.
It's gotta be... all the purple is gone.
Or pink, I should say.
Well, I guess we're not getting high anymore.
Shit.
I had big plans for getting high here.
But all right.
We're doing that some other time.
That's a mage.
Oh, he didn't die.
Now he did.
Am I even hitting him?
Doesn't look like it.
Too much SEMA.
Uh-oh.
Seems to be flammable stuff.
I mean, it is some kind of light finish alcohol, right?
Bubble spark with trigger.
Oh, that wand is not bad.
0.6.
I mean, it is kind of bad.
Never mind.
All right.
I'm not sure I like the, uh, my current main wand here.
It's too slow.
I like it to go brr.
Hello.
Hand over your gold.
What the hell is this?
Swamp.
Okay.
Dude, I wonder how the, uh, overgrown cavern is going to look like now.
No mushrooms.
I guess it's going to look the same as the last time I was there, because there was no mushrooms there either.
Really want to kill this guy.
There we go.
Holds easy.
Okay.
1600 gold is not bad.
We lost a bit of HP.
We just need to find bloodlust or something similar so we can actually start using the heal that we found.
That is going to be transformative for this run.
As soon as we can heal like that, that's big.
Also, I just realized, unlimited spells is great, but it's actually, for a long run, it's actually not that great because you can't, you can get unlimited spells in the endgame.
So you could potentially not take the unlimited spells and get something else and then get the unlimited spells via other methods.
Even though it's a little bit cumbersome to do it that way, but you know, it works.
I really need fire resistance.
Oh man, the digging on this is so bad now.
In fact, when I stand closer, it's better.
Yeah.
All right, let's go through.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
He's here.
I can fight him though.
I can fight him.
Can I?
Can I fight him?
Oh no.
Let's take it, take him down here.
Uh-oh, uh-oh.
Uh-oh.
Shit.
Oh no, I'm going to die here.
Ah, it's over, I think.
Fucking steward as always is here to ruin the day.
Fuck.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Fucking steward, man.
Every time.
Oh, I hate this guy so much.
Rip.
I really wish he would just fucking disappear.
God damn it.
I really thought he would die to my to my insane wand that was shooting easily over 150 damage per shot with the double fireball stuff.
What?
Like he was completely immune to it.
Or at least he absorbed everything.
I thought it would be fast enough and hard hitting enough, but apparently not.
That was such a good run.
I think steward is the biggest nemesis in this game for me.
Yeah sure, I'll take that.
I'll take some arrows.
What is the point of these actually?
It does reduce spread a lot.
That's kind of a unique property, isn't it?
Minus 20 spread is quite a lot.
Normally you see like minus six or something.
I think reduced spread has minus 60.
So having three of these is actually the same as having one reduced spread.
It's just kind of crazy.
Poor man's reduced spread and you need more slots for it, of course, on a wand.
I mean that run pretty much ended when I killed myself almost when I had two HP, because that meant I had to anger the gods and from then on out it's just like...
Yeah, that's it.
When you anger the gods in this game, it's no good.
Like I had the perfect setup for not angering the gods, you know?
I just needed to not kill myself with that wand.
But you live, you learn.
Hopefully.
All right, I'm gonna get through here.
More water.
I have good aim here.
Hey, totally owning it.
Not bad.
Ah, yeah, let's go up here.
See what they're brewing?
Nothing.
Hey, miss.
How you doing?
Actually, I'm gonna go grab the tablet.
Kind of important.
I need to get that double money.
Whoa!
Hurta from the sky.
Actually, let me grab this before they disappear.
Now we're talking.
What's up, my friend?
The sound it makes when you hit them with the tablet is brutal.
Ugh, you just hear their guts spraying everywhere.
I can probably get through there, but I'm not gonna.
I'm going around.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, hello.
Trying to hide a chest for me.
Nice.
That's actually a problem.
Quick, get it.
Shit, I'm stuck.
Oh!
See, that's a situation where I should have thought the money's not worth it.
Just don't do it.
I don't think that money was worth losing, what is it, 24 HP.
It's like a trade-off.
That's how you should see it.
The transaction.
You pay for this gold with a bit of your life.
That's what the hemisphere is all about.
Can you make efficient trades like that?
And making more efficient trades is easier with the tablet.
Makes you a master tradesman.
But it's a bit risky, because it is difficult to hit them with the tablet.
Whoa, whoa, water that.
Actually, is that that swamp?
Still works.
There we go.
And the other guy died from fire.
That's amazing.
Also dropped two.
He died from fire.
He dropped two gold nuggets.
But somehow he only dropped one, which I don't understand.
Crap.
Oh no, this is a bad situation.
We gotta kill the normal way.
Too risky.
Uh, acid potion?
Yeah, actually, I'll take it.
Better in my hands than on the floor.
More safe that way.
600 gold, not bad.
I will go around.
Oh, what's happening there?
Someone's pheromone.
Let's check it out.
Oh, he died, I guess.
Spark bolts.
And a lot of them.
I think that may be better.
Actually, it's hard to say.
Why can I hit them?
They were pheromone.
Usually, they're immune to my spells when they're pheromoned.
Some of these things I don't understand in this game.
Like, when I pheromone enemies, I usually can't hit them.
But now I can.
Give me the gold.
What have we got here?
Nice.
That was a 200 gold nugget.
That's huge.
I love just falling, and then throwing that tablet mid fall.
Like, express delivery.
Okay.
I think we're good.
Let's go.
A thousand gold.
Not bad at all.
I'm gonna save this heart.
Nice.
That is a huge spell to get here.
One of my favorites for this area.
And look at this!
Fire immunity!
Even better than the one I had before, which was toxic.
And this wand right here is sick!
Although it does have 30 spread, which is really bad.
But look at this!
I have three arrows I can put on and completely eliminate that.
In fact, just two of them will do it.
That is a great wand.
I may just get it.
And I'm gonna get this, of course.
That's a huge one.
Love the chain bolts.
I do love the light as well.
Actually, all of these are great.
Then we get this.
This is gonna be the main one.
And the eggs can fuck off.
Put them in the water.
Yeah, get rid of them.
And that's my wand!
It'll probably make it better.
Actually, this is...
I feel like this may even work a little bit.
Because it's gonna aim towards the enemy anyway, right?
Yeah, we should definitely put that on a triple spell or something, if I were to do that.
Maybe the spread is fine with this.
This is the one wand where the spread is actually okay.
Although that is a big spread.
Look at this.
Yikes.
Although 45 mana charge speed is kind of low.
Dude, this one is legitimately better.
This one is a better long-term wand.
We can probably fix that wand later with the right spells.
Yeah, that's better.
It does run out of mana.
About the same as the other one, but that's fine.
Heavy spread.
I think I'm fine here.
Put this up there.
I want to replace all these wands except this one.
Unless I find something better, of course.
Okay, that's that taken care of.
Digging.
Do we have any energy orbs or similar?
Wait, we do?
Wait, this is not the digging one.
This is the small one.
This will dig a little bit.
But it's not...
We definitely don't have a way to get out of this place without angering the gods.
Or we cannot even anger the gods.
So I guess we just let it collapse and that's that.
I think I may get one of these just because there's a timer on it.
Oh, but it costs 50 mana drain?
Damn.
That's an expensive one, but I'll take it.
I paid for it, so that
is expensive.
I don't know if I should buy this.
No, no, I don't want it.
I'm good with this.
This is fine.
Now I just need to find a way to get back in here when I need to heal.
You know what?
Maybe I should just heal.
I am collapsing the mountain.
I'm not intending to come back.
Well, at least not in the near future.
Let's go.
Very simple setup here.
Plate safe.
Oh, nice.
Look at that.
Now I regret healing.
I could have healed that up if I went back after that.
The game has a way of being funny at times and cruel at the same time.
We have a dude down there.
You see that?
He has a wand.
That's for you.
Have fun, son.
Oh, he missed.
Oh, he came back.
Nice.
Okay, okay.
Bro, how much HP do you possess?
Yo, sick!
A chainsaw with a spark bolt.
That's a great little pickup.
Thanks.
Not bad.
Thank you.
Do I even take damage from that glitter?
I don't think I do.
Okay, all I need now is to become explosion immune, electricity immune, toxic immune.
I need tinker with wands everywhere.
And then I need to find all the right spells and then I'm good.
That's all I need.
Oh, I see a heart.
I see a heart.
The heart is spotted.
Wait, can I get in there?
Don't you aim up there, you asshole.
Wait, this does dig though.
There's a chainsaw.
Not very efficient, but it works.
Man, that one turns really fast.
I thought it didn't have enough time to turn.
I was wrong.
I'm kind of...
Okay, I'm back.
Thought I was stuck.
Nice.
Sweet.
This is absolutely my favorite spell for this part of the game.
The chain...
I am so well set right now.
And with the fire immunity too.
Almost can't ask for better than this.
I think I had 110 HP, right?
When I came in here.
So I actually only lost nine.
Oh God.
Look how much chaos killing that one enemy did.
Or cost.
Maybe a golden rule here is to not kill these guys when you're below them.
But sometimes you have to.
Like you could put rules in place in your mind for all enemies like that.
You know, oh, this enemy you don't want to kill it from below.
This enemy you'd want to kill him from afar.
Some months you're gonna get close to.
What the hell?
All right.
I'm trying to think of ways to minimize chaos.
And up my chances of survival.
Doesn't that look like a dildo?
Ah, wait a minute.
No, nothing here.
Ah, ah, man.
Okay, look at this.
It's always the same.
This is like total deja vu.
I was here just before digging.
Man, I don't want to do this again.
Fuck.
But I'll do it.
Get rid of the top, please.
There we go.
Yes.
Almost.
I'm trying to line my character up such that the spark of the chainsaw aligns with the thing I want to destroy.
Nice.
Kind of scuffed digging there, but it works.
Not very beautiful.
Ah, wait, I was here already.
Fuck.
Apparently, I can't go left with my current getup.
I'll have to find some more wands.
I've been down there.
Wait, am I closed off again?
Is this one of those?
Probably not, I'm fine.
Sometimes you can get unlucky and actually not have anywhere to go in here if you don't have digging.
Just by pure RNG.
It happens sometimes, but it's very rare.
Okay,
I want to go up now.
Then right.
Look at that.
Start with the top and then we go down.
Dead end.
Now, am I getting the same?
Like this kind of looks similar to what I saw before as well.
Hold on, is there a harden here?
Oh my god!
Look at the shape!
Okay, it's not actually quite the same.
Maybe something is missing here, but it looked almost the same.
I'm sniffing out all the hearts here, man.
What's happening?
This is very unprecedented.
Also, this is Colvane, right?
This is going to take forever.
Can I not?
Can I really not?
Wow, that doesn't dig at all?
Oh, this is painful.
The things you do to get the hearts.
There's a little piece right there that I can't get rid of.
There we go, I think I got it.
Get that one.
I've kind of read...
Okay, so just on a tangent here.
I've reached the point in this game where...
Similar to World of Warcraft, funnily enough.
You know how when you...
So I don't know if you play World of Warcraft, but maybe you have played the original World of Warcraft.
The music in that game is phenomenal, right?
Like, it's just iconic.
You know, Elwynn Forest or the Barrens, Mulgore, all those places, right?
Great.
But that game takes a while, you know?
It takes a while to level up.
And after a certain time, while the music is great, you kind of stop listening to the in-game music, you know?
You need a break from it.
I'm starting to get that feeling with Noita, where I kind of want to put on my own music while playing.
You know what I mean?
It feels like a crime in a single player game.
But let's be honest, the music is not very varied in this game, is it?
Like, it's nice, but it's very the same.
It's like, very similar all the time.
Also, did I just do something great?
Oh no, it was a burst of air.
Uh, I mean, the wand is not bad.
I want to say this wand is respectable in its stats.
As a real wand aficionado.
Although this one has a low mana charge, lower mana max, but it does have better...
Oh, never mind.
It only has two slots.
What am I talking about?
I'm not a real wand aficionado.
I was lying.
I missed the obvious thing.
What's that though?
Ah, an egg.
Nope.
I reject the egg.
Always reject the egg.
Do we have a heart in there?
My heart radar is buzzing!
Oh wait, I see an enemy.
Also, I'm not gonna dig unless I am 100% certain.
Hold on, did I find something that can dig down here?
Can that dig?
No, probably not.
As soon as I find a wand that can dig a little bit, I'm taking it.
Like a bomb or something.
Thanks.
1200 gold.
It's very good.
Did I just see a...
Ah, hello.
You little bastard.
Man, this thing crits for 120.
And the best part about this chain wand or the chain bolt is that it's also fantastic against all the enemies in the fungal cavern, especially these little fucking assholes.
Little chungus, chungus frogs.
I don't have to be able to aim.
They jump around all the time and you just kill them.
It's great.
Oh, okay.
We got a shotgun man.
And a mage!
He is prioritized here.
He's down.
That's another one.
We gotta get high again.
We obviously gotta do that.
I do wonder what the probabilities are of...
Like what exactly is hard coded into this game of getting a beneficial one or a bad one?
Because there's definitely something that can be said is always bad for you, right?
Like you don't want something to be turned into lava.
Ever.
Or if it's just like completely random.
Any one element to any other element, you know?
Broken wand, very nice.
So before I get high...
I am gonna...
Maybe I do need the demon eye for this actually.
Maybe after I got high once on the platform, I need the demon eye to see that something changed.
Maybe it will even show me one out of three or something.
I don't know.
At this point, I'm really grasping at straws.
When it comes to the hole getting high in the fungal caverns.
Man, it feels bad not being able to dig.
I feel so limited.
Guess I'll go this way.
It's a little dangerous, but...
Okay.
That was smooth.
Holy shit.
Okay, where is he?
Where is he?
Where'd you go?
Maybe he's gonna come back.
Oh, hello.
Get him.
Pheromone.
Hell yeah.
Get rid of this.
Love me some pheromone.
Uh-oh, that's a lot of enemies.
Why is this not hitting anything?
What's happening?
Come on.
There we go.
Slowly but surely.
That's the way forward.
Look at it.
You know how in movies when characters always run away from something coming towards them?
And they just keep running away when they could just sidestep.
I always curse at them and go like, go to the side, you idiot!
And now I'm doing the same thing here.
You know what?
Always when those slow projectiles come at me, I just run the same way it comes.
Why don't I just go up or down?
You know, I'm starting to feel for the people in the movies.
The characters, the things they do under stress, you know, it makes sense.
Get rid of that.
Personal fireball thrower.
I don't think I like it.
The personal stuff there is a little weird.
Kill him.
By the way, this thing right here...
Here's the thing, actually.
If I get hit by this, I'm fucked.
So if someone picks this up and shoots me with this, I think that's game over.
So I may just take it with me, actually.
I will not leave it behind.
I'm going to put it somewhere safe in a vault.
This guy is a polymorph man.
He died quick.
Minimizing chaos here.
Shit, shit, shit, shit.
I'm firing Moon, that's right.
Get the gold.
Ah, I can't make it.
Oh no.
Stay calm, stay calm, stay calm.
Stay calm, we're fine.
Control the teleport.
B1 with the teleport.
Also kill things through the wall.
That's the way to go.
How did I...
Oh, please die.
Thanks.
Look at them shooting each other.
Wait, what?
Hold on, I want to kill one of them.
Actually, let me...
What are you doing to me?
Wait, what?
Are you giving me mana?
What the
hell are they doing to me?
They're doing something and it's not hurting me.
Come on.
Now they're hitting each other with it.
Guys, come on.
Do not hit it, come on.
I need to kill one of them.
Okay, now.
Oh wait, do they charm me or did I charm myself?
What are you doing to me?
I mean, I think it's something new with invisibility, because they shot it on each other and one of them briefly became transparent.
But it's not working on me.
Oh wait, maybe it's because I'm stained.
Hold on.
Let me try and get rid of it.
Actually, I've been walking around in this stuff all the time.
Oh, wait, whoa.
Got him.
Oh, big car...
Oh, he got...
Well, okay.
Guess that's not happening.
He got teleported away.
Okay.
Now, there's a one in there.
I kind of want to get it.
Wait a minute, have I...
What is this tablet?
Is that mine?
Blood mist.
Nah, I'm good fam.
Why is this here?
What is this tablet?
It's got to be the one I left.
Yeah, it's the one I left.
I remember throwing it now.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, that was a mistake.
See, I shouldn't have done that.
I got lucky there.
In fact, we are kind of low HP.
It's probably time to get the hell out.
Invisiblium.
Should I take that?
You know, Invisiblium is super helpful if I'm low HP and I need to get through an area.
But I kind of want to keep the pheromone for now.
Pheromone is big.
I'll be back here later to get high.
Let's get the hell out.
Oh, no.
Ah, damn it.
What is the way out of here?
Oh, wait, I came from here.
I remember this.
Let's be careful.
40 HP.
It's very low.
Okay.
2000 gold, man.
That is a lot.
We can buy everything here.
Now we're fucking talking.
Look at that.
Black hole teleport.
More chain bolts.
Fireball orbits.
We've got a heavy spread and we've got all kinds of stuff.
Look at that explosion immunity.
Yo, that's what I'm saying.
Next, I'm going to need electricity immunity, toxic immunity and all the other good stuff.
Very cool.
And this is a decent wand as well.
Like a lot of slots on it.
Better than this one.
I'll take it.
Thanks.
Actually, this one is not bad.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Let me deposit some of the important stuff up here first.
Yeah, sure.
Keep it up.
Nah, I'm never going to use that.
Fuck that.
I will never use it.
Maybe we only need one light.
We don't need that many of these.
Do I even need any of these?
Probably not.
Fireballs.
Let's put them in a neat pile over here.
This is the fireball pile.
This light can go here, because why not?
Okay, now we can take some wands.
Let's get that one.
Give me this one and that one.
So many lights!
Fireball orbit.
Actually, hold on, I'm immune to fire.
That would be amazing.
And a triple, I'll take it.
The wand itself is kind of meh.
Goes in the meh wand pile down there.
Do I want more chain bolts?
Maybe not.
It is not a small teleport bolt.
It is just a normal one, but it's still good.
A disc projectile.
Let's keep that here.
Get rid of that.
Black hole is super nice.
Actually, we just need one.
Later on, we can make it infinite.
So a singular black hole will do all the difference later on.
Two heavy spreads.
And a chainsaw.
We ought to be able to make something amazing here.
Oh, this is shuffled, actually.
0.1, 0.07.
Also, the mana on that is bad.
0.53, 0.12.
I need a just decent wand here.
That's actually better than this one.
Or than that one, I guess.
Put some of these on here.
I'm going to get more chain bolts.
Maybe one is fine.
We can make it faster.
We are limited by recharge time, for sure.
Wait, what?
0.17.
Oh, but hold on.
Chain bolt adds a lot of castelay.
That explains it.
So we are limited by castelay right now, actually.
Even though it's hard to say, it's so fast.
It goes by so fast.
It's hard to say what's actually happening there.
Now, that one is just bad.
We don't want to be shooting in completely random directions.
Honestly, it's just as fast without it.
Maybe just a tiny difference.
Teleport is obviously a must.
That one is a little bit too slow.
That sounds better.
Even though it feels like a waste, let's put it on that one instead.
Yeah, this is our teleport.
This is our damage.
Yeah, nice.
I like it.
Black hole.
See, I don't know if I want to equip that yet, because having three, it's not a lot, and then I can't replace my wands.
I do like having some open slots for wands that I find.
What happens if I put fireball orbit on chain bolt?
Oh, that is actually intriguing.
And here's why.
The lifetime of the fireball orbit is bigger.
You see, you can actually see them slowly rotate.
Pretty cool.
Okay, now the chainsaw.
We can do a little bit of digging with that.
And chainsaw doesn't care about heavy spread, so we can probably just do something like this on one of the wands.
Maybe that one, honestly.
Look at that!
It does cost a lot of mana though.
Do we even need this?
Not really.
It's not fantastic digging, but it's digging.
It's going to dig through soft stuff.
Not the hard stuff though.
Yeah.
And this one is an acceptable teleport wand, I guess.
It could be worse.
Is there anything else I should buy here?
I don't think so.
I think I'm good.
Put this up here.
How about, is it worth it to do this?
On one...
You know what?
I'm going to keep it up here so I can replace these wands.
Yeah, fuck it.
Let's just go.
Kill him.
I'm curious to see how much better the fireball orbit is now.
Because it's moving slower through the air.
It gives it more time.
So let's say there's like three enemies, right?
I cast it.
Because if it's too fast, they're never going to impact anything.
Explosion on drunk enemies.
Man, I don't want a fucking recharge time of three seconds.
Are you kidding me?
No, don't...
See, as soon as I don't have poison resistance, then I get poisoned.
Or toxic, I should say.
I thought I just killed a rat with my teleport, but it was just oddly weirdly timed.
See, now I regret not having my chainsaw, but it's fine.
Homing!
And a magic arrow with trigger.
I like it.
I do.
Now we just need to find unlimited spells.
I think the fireball orbit is doing great here.
Like it's hard to say, of course, but it feels really good.
It feels really good.
Let's check it out on this guy.
The only issue is I don't have a lot of range.
This electricity scares me!
Okay, so it's definitely kind of bad at dealing with mechanical enemies.
My one is not that great at that.
Which, also, Chain Bolt is not the best spells for this area.
Simply because of the long distances involved with some of these engagements.
I have to remember, I'm fire immune and explosion immune.
I can really allow myself to be kind of brazen.
I hear electricity!
Hello!
How are you doing?
So here's my plan.
Sick!
Okay, he needs three shots of that?
Yeah, that's scary.
Just don't take any damage.
We're playing in slow motion today.
Let's not forget.
Oh, hello!
Whoa, the dodging!
Now, I have a feeling something's going on in here.
No, no, there's not.
I remember this look.
The tile, tile set, whatever you want to call it.
Wait, did I just block...
No, I think I blocked the explosive element of his projectile, because that projectile has an explosive element.
Okay, also be careful of water.
I wonder what happens if I put homing on chain bolt, because chain bolt is already kind of homing?
I wonder if it's gonna make it omega homing, just even more aggressive.
Those are the combinations that intrigue me.
Sweet.
I really should be going for some kind of explosion...
explosive projectile build, because I'm immune to fire and explosive damage.
So I can just go ham with that stuff.
There's a sniper and that scares me right now, because I don't really have any way of dealing with him.
Oh, nice!
He went there.
Thanks, bro.
Where'd he go?
Enemies are falling from the sky.
Always nice.
Why is that thing not exploding?
There we go.
Show yourself.
Like, who just puts a bunch of acid in a huge box and leaves it there?
Freaks.
Oh, I can sort of dig with this!
But it's not great.
It works.
Kinda.
That's not fantastic.
Very unreliable digging, similar to the orbiting chainsaws digging.
Sawblades.
The sawblades.
118.
I can stay a little longer.
By the way, so some of these enemies are obviously friends.
Like, the Heezy people are all on the same side.
Or a faction, I guess.
I wonder if I take the more love.
If the different...
Like, so he was attacking this blue guy.
I wonder if I take that perk, if they will not fight each other anymore.
That's probably what that means, right?
Also, what is happening here?
There's actually writing on the brickwork.
I think.
Maybe not.
Kinda looked like there was something there.
Oh wait, am I hearing a electricity man?
Hello?
Gotcha.
Somehow, I'm just super flush with money.
This run.
More acid, no thanks.
Oh no, I hate these guys so much.
The fire resistance helps.
Holy crap, look at all that.
That looks like hell itself.
What a mess.
I mean, I can go in there.
I'm immune.
I'm totally fine.
Give me the gold!
Okay, I can't go up there.
I'm tempted to just keep going now.
But let's just explore a bit more.
I think the right side is begging for a bit of exploration.
If I had returned, I could quickly go in and have a look-see and come out again.
Actually, I don't have enough time.
I have just about enough time to grab the health in there and then get out again with return.
Because that was super close.
That was almost on the millisecond, I feel like.
Last time I tried that.
And I timed it pretty well.
Okay, so I...
Wait a minute.
The acid is gone.
It all became flammable gas on its own.
I wonder why.
Man, I explored all the way over here.
Okay, here we go.
Oh, you bastard!
I hate when you see something coming and you're trying to avoid it and you still get hit.
That's the worst feeling.
Because you prepared for it.
Okay, that guy I just didn't see.
He was camouflaged inside of that water.
Oh god!
Get him out of here.
Oh shit!
No!
Okay, we gotta leave.
I gotta sneeze!
The sneeze won't come out.
It's very triggering right now.
Also, we have a worm situation here, I believe.
Fuck, how do I...
Wait a minute.
I got him.
Uh, that's a very interesting wand, actually.
I hear electricity.
Okay, we're leaving.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Do not stay any longer.
What do we got?
What's that?
Hey, toxic immunity!
Oh, but I really want to take this though.
No, but I gotta take toxic immunity.
Look at my immunity.
I wasn't kidding at the beginning.
I was like, I need this immunity, that immunity, that immunity.
And the game's like, all right, sir, I heard you.
Here you go.
Very nice.
Okay, um, get rid of some stuff.
I'll take these.
There we go.
And then...
What do I want here?
I feel like, so here's my issue.
This is the big problem I have in this run.
I don't have a good wand.
Straight up, I don't have a good damage wand.
So I'm gonna need to make one.
Unfortunately, all of my wands kind of suck.
This is the best.
Maybe the best is simply a magic arrow with a chainsaw.
Like, it sounds dumb, but I think that's the best I've got at this point.
From what I've got here, you know, I mean, the chain-pole is nice.
But it's not that nice.
Actually, maybe I will keep it on this.
Just when I need to hit things behind a wall.
Oh, but the mana charge here is terrible.
Ah, it's because of this.
Let's just do that.
It's kind of slow.
It kind of sucks, but it is what it is.
Or maybe I just...
No, you know what?
No, we're just gonna rock with that.
Keep it simple.
And maybe get a one black hole.
Nah, yeah, nah, do I?
Hmm.
I don't know.
Homing.
I think I'm good.
Let me see the spells again.
Wooplycage spell?
What?
Cast copies of a projectile in a trifurcated pattern, but the copies still cost mana.
Wooplycage!
That sounds fun.
Avoiding arc.
Magic bolt, maybe.
I don't like any of these, really.
Not a huge fan.
All right.
Fuck, we can't get out of here, unfortunately, still.
So we still can't make an HQ.
It sucks, but it is what it is.
Yeah.
Uh-oh, that's a lot of people.
I gotta get to a safer spot.
Just wait here for them.
Come on, one at a time.
Form an orderly line.
Beautiful.
Very nice.
Okay, so look at this.
A simple magic arrow with trigger and a chainsaw is actually already kind of dope.
Like, it's super simple, but it gets the job done.
Then again, I haven't met any super strong enemies down here yet.
Like, I haven't met any mechanicals, so.
But just the people here?
Not bad.
It'll do.
And we have a broken wand.
Let's go try it on the forge.
Or the anvil.
Okay, not bad.
I can dig it.
That worked pretty well.
I'm not being greedy.
I'm not...
Oh!
Friendos!
That's right.
I forgot about those.
We gotta keep those in mind.
The...
Oh!
The friendos.
I was scratching my eyebrow exactly when he shot.
I'm not kidding.
I had my right hand off the mouse on my eyebrow.
Very unlucky.
Nice.
Oh, that's electric.
The berserkium here is...
No, the friendo!
In the line of fire.
Uh,
drink some more of this.
Beautiful.
I feel like this thing needs to blow up.
That is right!
Circle of buoyancy.
I can't really get up there, unfortunately.
I mean, do I even have blood?
Or...
I don't even have any of the stuff I need.
But this is the prime opportunity to try something new.
I kind of want to try and put something like acid in there.
Even though it's probably gonna eat through the glass.
Who knows?
Fucking chemists have acid and glass, right?
Should work.
Wait!
Fucking asshole.
That was a fake chest.
I can't dig at all.
That's the big downside to my build right here.
I see wand.
Holy shit, that's a lot.
I should probably blow that up.
Come on, blow!
What the hell?
Dude, the magic arrow does no damage to explosives, what's happening?
I feel like I'm on New Year's Eve right now.
I dare not go back to the firework after it didn't work, you know?
All right, fine, just go.
There we go.
Get him out of here.
Hey, guys.
Have fun.
It's gonna blow.
Next.
These assholes still got me!
Unreal.
Holy shit, what's that?
Anti-homing.
No, thanks.
A lot of these wands always contain a weird ass combination of spells.
Like, why is it always a million of one type, you know?
It's a weird thing that's going on in this game.
Blow it.
It'll be okay here, right?
Yeah.
Now that blows.
It's painful.
I gotta find a friendo.
Or I bomb him down here.
Hey, sir!
Hey, that works.
I don't think I got the mechanical one.
No, I didn't.
Ouch.
Okay, I really need a friendo now.
Are you kidding me?
What a shot!
Bounces like here, Duke, Duke into me.
That's why I hate these guys so much.
I always get hit by their bullshit.
The projectiles just always manage to find their way into my face.
It's my Achilles heel, for sure.
Again.
Automana.
What?
Oh my god, dude.
Okay.
Jesus Christ.
God damn, dude.
Oh, I didn't pay attention to how many deaths I had.
But it should be, I think, under 100 now because of the corrupted save file.
Ah.
My Achilles heel, man.
I have two archnemesis right now in the game.
Arch-nemesis, I guess you would say.
Obviously, Stuart.
But also those guys.
But also the people that polymorph.
Basically, a lot of enemies are a problem for me in this game.
Let's be real.
I don't have it easy with anyone.
God fucking damn it, man.
Here we go again.
Fireball.
Yeah.
Set everything on fire.
These guys, honestly, are also one of my worst enemies.
Just their slow projectiles mess with my brain.
Absolutely hate them so much.
It's almost like they've been designed to fuck with me.
Like me specifically the most, you know?
Probably not, but it feels that way.
This guy's a wand.
Hello.
Hamis!
That was a bit scary.
That's a bomb.
Where did the fireman go?
Wow, he really went far.
He went up here.
What?
Oh, that's alcohol.
Water?
Nice.
I need water.
When do you not need water in this game?
Oh, wrong button.
I meant to do this one.
There we go.
Now this here, I think I'm just gonna burn it.
Yeah, trigger that.
Most obvious trap.
Uh, I'll take it.
Yeah.
Polymorphine.
And a heart.
Solid start, actually.
I'm liking.
In fact, I've gotten some really good runs today here.
Like the beginnings are solid.
I'm really happy about that.
No, I don't want to take that.
Keep the arrows.
I wonder if there's an actual good wand you can make with arrows.
Probably, right?
Make it shoot really fast.
Give them some damage.
Hey.
Stop that.
I thought that was a puzzle.
Looked like one of those whiskey puzzles.
By the last...
Wait.
No, that's blood.
Man,
I want to find more things to translate.
But I gotta get through the beginnings here.
I do wonder, maybe I should stop trying to aim for like the most amazing endgame.
And just go for something passable where I can start exploring.
You know?
Because even if I get almighty powerful, and literally nothing can stop me type powerful, I can still get polymorph and then it's just over.
So, spending too much time is maybe not the brightest idea.
Maybe I want to find a sweet spot of my power curve, so to speak.
How do I get in here?
Let me just make a hole here.
I'm trying to look for that opening for so long.
Whoa, nice!
See, that's huge.
Already really nice.
What do we got?
Vampirism!
That's the guaranteed run!
There it is!
We're saved!
Oh, that's amazing.
That is what we need to kickstart everything.
That is the great guarantee that I've been looking for.
Uh, do I want any of these ones for...
Nah, I'm just gonna use my chain bolt.
Good old chain bolt.
That's too slow.
That's too slow in mana.
That's acceptable, although mana recharge is still a little bit iffy.
0.17, 0.3.
Oh, okay, this maybe could work.
It's a little better.
Yeah, yeah.
Can we make it even better?
Maybe that one.
It says 5-2 recharge, 5-3.
Yeah.
Oh, I can't afford it.
Shit.
That's okay.
This is actually a fine wand.
It's a fine wand, yes.
And that's about it.
Do I need a rain cloud at all?
Maybe.
Don't think so.
I do need to get rid of the polymorphine, though.
And fill that bad boy with blood ASAP.
Uh, where do I put it?
Probably nowhere in here.
I'm going to leave all these wands empty to be replaced.
Yeah, let's just leave here and get rid of the polymorphine, start collecting some blood, and things are starting to look up.
What's a good spot?
I need something kind of huge.
Like a huge bat or something.
Look at this!
It's the same tileset, but it's like cut off.
Where there was a heart.
Is there a heart?
There's no heart.
Actually kind of looks like a foot.
Doesn't that kind of look like the heel?
Toes?
You know?
Looks like Italy.
If Italy wasn't a boot, but a foot instead, which is not, so never mind.
Now, uh, polymorphine.
Let's put you...
There!
This is a great spot, I think.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's bigger than I thought.
Look, another foot!
Right?
I'm not crazy.
There's feet everywhere.
I can't unsee it now.
Here we go.
I will never come back to this spot.
This is the safest area to dispose of this.
For sure.
I got to say, though, for how deadly polymorphine is, it is beautiful.
I do like the way it looks.
Oh, wait, I don't have teleport anymore.
My muzzle memory is already messing with me.
Like, how lucky do I get here to get chain bolt twice in a row for this area?
Oh, fuck, this is a dead end.
No digging capabilities.
...yet.
But I just feel so optimistic.
Like, just having the vampirism is like...
It's pretty much a guarantee to get to the endgame now, no matter what.
Unless I, you know, something really crazy happens.
Other than that, I'm pretty safe right now.
Such a great feeling.
Okay, take some water also.
Oh, and by the way, I forgot to mention this.
Remember in the frozen caverns, or whatever it's called, frozen wastes?
There was this inscription on the wall that I took a picture of.
I actually did figure out, or watch a YouTube video on how to read music.
Or like, how to read notes.
And I think I know what it says now.
So, I need to get the musical instrument and try my combination.
But it's been a while since I saw that video.
I did it almost straight after playing Noita last time.
Because I had it fresh in my mind.
Okay,
now we go up this way.
Okay, I feel like I'm being closed in here again.
It's not a good feeling.
Especially when you don't have a dick in your hand.
Wait, wait, I don't have a way to destroy the chest.
Do it!
Oh, we're blessed with gold.
I was being a little bit risky there.
I don't know why I did that.
That was a mistake.
We have vampirism.
This is the run.
Why am I being risky like that?
We've got hoodlums.
Very good.
We actually went from 100 to 400 almost with that chest.
Not bad at all.
Also, I can't forget.
I got to pick up the blood.
Kind of a big deal here.
Oh, I'm stuck.
Disc projectiles.
I think I would like some.
Why not?
Get them.
Love the chain pull.
I can't say it enough.
Jesus Christ.
What is happening?
I think they threw a bunch of acid bottles.
Right when the explosion happened, and it was just a weird miasma of chaos.
Uh oh.
No!
No, I just said it!
It's acid!
God damn it.
It's okay.
That was a mistake.
I moused over it.
You know what I thought in my mind?
I don't...
This is going to sound like an excuse, okay?
But I swear to you.
So you know how acid kind of looks like toxic waste?
I identified that that was acid, okay?
I saw it.
But then...
I started going off to...
I was saying something.
I forgot what I said.
But then I...
I was flying.
I was hovering.
And I just saw that toxic waste that I thought was toxic waste above some water.
And I thought, oh, it's going to mix.
And become water, you know?
I'm fine to go in there.
It's going to become water.
Because I'm...
You know, they mix like this.
So in my mind, I fucking went in there expecting...
Oh, I could just go below and take no damage, you know?
God damn it.
I had vampirism.
By the way, I think I've changed my mind.
Vampirism is the best perk in this game.
For me.
Because it is what allows me to start owning.
You know?
Okay, this is fine.
I've been blessed with good starts.
I'm sure this will be a good run as well.
I'm sure the first holy mountain will contain healing.
Vampirism, which is also healing.
And black hole and teleport.
I guarantee it.
Can I get in there?
Yes, I can.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Stay away.
Let the grown-ups handle this.
Shit.
No!
Oh, wait, that's actually fine.
That should blow it up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, beautiful.
I
want...
Sick!
I'm being given way too many second chances today.
I can't squander this one, guys.
That's a really nice one.
Oh, no, don't poison yourself.
I'm actually so happy I got that.
And look at this.
It's even an energy orb.
That means we got a dig.
I can't fuck this up now.
This is a great one.
Also, I did kind of forget.
What other plants did I have?
There was something else I wanted to do.
Something specific today.
Which one was it?
It was not that one.
It was something with polymorph...
Not this one.
So I found two polymorphines today.
I need to bring it to the west of Lake.
For reasons that I can't explain.
I actually need to write down before I forget.
Oh, it's not connected.
Hold on a second.
There we go.
Now I can type.
No, don't do that.
Use...
Uh...
What was it?
I already forgot now.
Fuck, what was it?
Oh yeah, right, right, right.
Try.
Cave.
Music.
With music wand.
Just so I don't forget.
Okay.
Back we go.
So, and I don't need much to get the music wand.
That's what I meant before when I said I don't need to reach amazing levels of power.
To start experimenting with some of these things, you know.
I don't need to get like uber powered.
If I can just get some extra levitation potion or whatever.
I can start getting up there, you know, and get that wand.
And then I can try that stuff.
Ooh, I almost destroyed that.
Let's not do that.
Also, I see you down there.
What if I were to...
Nah, I'm just gonna kill you.
Shit.
Ooh!
He blew up the alcohol.
At least I think he did.
Man, the firebolt is surprisingly effective.
Nice.
I think that's my go-to spell.
If I ever have trouble with these people, just get the firebolt out.
Set fire to him, that's the solution.
But a righteous fire, not his fire.
What is it with these potions?
Look at this.
Phlamoxium, chaotic polymorphine, and polymorphine.
I'm carrying around the worst combinations of items.
Where's my Ambrosia, or my blood, or Berserkium, or something?
This guy is not dying.
Hello?
What a guy!
Oh my god.
He just did like 10 damage.
Well, it was worth it.
Got the money.
This guy has a lot of HP.
There we go.
That's how we deal with those.
Water this.
I can't fucking believe I went into the acid still.
I'm still thinking about it.
What is wrong with me?
I want to get up there.
Oh, but wait a minute, I can dig with this?
Of course I can.
A bomb.
Yeah.
I'll take it.
In fact, put this here instead.
Dude, this thing is going to slap, actually.
Why am I not just using this for damage?
Oh, it's very inaccurate, actually.
For some reason, it's...
Why is it so inaccurate?
Oh, 22 spread, plus this ad spread.
I see why.
I see.
But at close quarters, it's maybe okay.
Oh my god.
Oh!
Dude, I'm playing this so bad.
I feel like I've lost all my Noisa powers.
Water myself.
Get it.
Okay, now.
That works.
Nice.
No acid here.
Everything's fine.
Oh, that was beautiful.
Did you see the bounce?
Also, this man has a wand.
We gotta let him know that that's not okay.
Oh my god.
Now he has a wand!
It's actually a scary spell he has.
It's the triplicate bolt.
At least these guys can't pick up wands, right?
Just the triplicate bolt.
Actually, the wand is not bad.
It only has two slots, though.
That's the downside here.
Um...
I'll take it.
Uh...
What?
Was I just super low HP or what?
I got hit by three at the same time, I think.
Oh, man.
Fuck.
Oh, no.
And I have acid!
The game is trying to rub it in now.
Well, you think I'm gonna falter?
You think I'm gonna be dissuaded?
Where did all this water come from?
Nobody knows.
Hold on, I can get in here.
No, no, no.
Like, why the bomb gotta do that?
Come on, burn, burn, burn.
Yes, make a hole for...
Yes, make a hole for me, dig for me.
Dig for me.
Yes!
Circle of shielding!
Sweet!
What exactly does that do again?
Right.
It's actually really good.
And I can shoot from inside of it.
Dude, this is the ultimate steward killer.
Not ultimate, but it's pretty good.
Nice!
Dude, the game is so nice right now.
Giving me all these things.
Nice, he went into the bomb.
Nice!
Dude, I'm owning right now.
Just gotta keep it up.
I kind of like this, where did all this water come from?
Because it means, well, all the fires are gonna get put out, and all the toxic is gonna be gone, and I'm gonna...
I will murder this him with acids.
Watch this.
Sup, guys?
Oh, shit.
Yeah, what's up?
How you doing?
Wait, I'm killing myself here.
This is not actually working out the way I thought it would.
No!
No, Hamis, I'm sorry!
Ah, why did I try to be cute about it?
I got instantly punished.
What is wrong with me?
It was fun.
All right, I'm gonna put the acid here now.
In fact, look at this, it dissolves immediately, becomes flammable gas.
Before it even hits the ground.
I definitely deserved that one just now.
Whoa!
Like, I was trying to gas the Hamis.
I mean, that's just evil.
And I got punished.
I did.
I come into their house, you know, and start doing stuff like that.
I get it.
Nice.
Now there's Hamis up here as well.
I'm just gonna kill them normally in the respectful way, the dual way.
Whoa!
Look at these eyes up here.
They're having a party.
Those are hortas.
The horta population needs to be culled as well, though.
Just can't have them wandering around like that.
Great.
Now I'm gonna get the tablet.
Look at all this water.
Time for me to pick it up.
Okay, this time, I swear to God, there's gonna be healing, vampirism, teleport, and that's it.
That's gonna be in the next holy mountain.
Oh, that's a bit precarious.
Hold on.
That's better, that better be a good wand.
That is a good...
No, it's the energy sphere, it's not an energy orb.
Ah, it's bad.
Damn it.
I thought I got super lucky.
Also, I should probably...
I'm gonna get the tablet for this dude.
I gotta read him the 10 commandments.
Hey, sir!
Have you heard of the 10th commandments?
Oh, seems like he has.
Okay, nice.
Man, even with a full-on tablet hit, he still survives.
548 gold.
I think I'm okay to go, but I would love to get just a single heart.
Just a single.
Whoa.
Okay, actually, there is a lot of water here.
I wonder if those pipes will keep expelling water forever, because that will eventually flood this place.
I never thought about that.
Oh, shit.
Ah, wait, wait.
This pipe is not...
Actually, it is dripping water.
Kinda.
This place has become a sewer.
Next.
Ooh, nice a chest.
Yes!
Thanks, game.
You're the best.
Hey, sir.
I love that.
This is for you.
Very cool.
A fireball is very welcome.
This guy needs to be tablet-ed.
He needs to be mentioned in a tabloid.
That was terrible.
Tableau-y!
All right, you want to die?
Let's not get cocky.
That's actually my downfall.
As soon as I get cocky, I die.
It's like karma hits me faster than anything else.
I want that wand.
Can I get it?
I can, I think.
This should dig it.
Yep.
It's very slow.
But it works.
Almost.
There we go.
But this is a trap, no?
Or what?
No, there's nothing here.
Is that a good wand?
250 max mana?
49?
It's better than...
Oh, yeah, it is.
It's better than this one.
I'll take it.
You see that?
It activated the...
Whatever that is.
The circuit.
But nothing happened because nothing was connected to the circuit.
I've never seen that.
Can't get to these guys.
Am I locked in here?
That's fine.
I just needed one more heart.
And I got it.
Let's leave.
Unless...
Oh, hold on.
That's actually...
What's up, dude?
Okay, that was sweet.
I thought this was locked off.
So now I can explore here.
Let me just quickly take a look before I leave.
It's not greedy.
I have 50 HP.
It's fine.
The frogs, though, are kind of crazy.
But...
Hold on.
That's for you.
Oh my god!
That was amazing.
Okay, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Don't tempt fate.
Do not become cocky.
Don't do it.
Oh, but look at this.
I am kind of a god, though.
Maybe just a demigod or something.
Yeah,
let him kill himself.
Play it safe.
Nice.
Water.
Crab.
We have a big frog there.
I think we should leave.
But then again, we do have explosives here.
There's things we can do with this.
Wait, isn't that just gonna explode now?
Yep.
Well, that's fine, though, because I can get in here now.
Oh, that's a dude.
Hand me the gold!
Thanks.
Water meself.
Just a bit more.
Kiva skeevy.
Yeah, sure, why not?
We can experiment with that, I guess.
I'm stuck.
And I really want to...
Look at him.
Look at that face.
He's sitting there gulping.
Yeah.
Fuck you.
That felt amazing.
Still at 50 HP, by the way.
Just saying.
Demigod confirmed.
Uh-oh.
Wait, where's my Firebolt?
I guess I gave it away.
Oh, he doesn't have too much range.
Ha!
No, no, no, no.
Ah, we're leaving.
We're leaving.
Yeah, we're leaving.
I think I lost my Demigod status just there at the end.
It was...
Yeah.
It fell off.
Ooh, nice.
We've got stuff.
A gamble!
Well, I'll take it.
A random always cast spell is added to the one in your hand.
Oh.
Fast to levitation.
Well, well, well.
All right, these are the cards I have been dealt.
I believe.
Now, what should I use it on?
That is crit, isn't it?
Kind of sad that it went on this wand.
Fuck.
Why did it go on that wand?
Bubble Spark is bad.
I don't know.
I mean, I guess...
It's kind of fast.
With this.
Gotta do that.
How about...
No, no, no.
We're about to head into an area with kind of long distance fighting.
I think I'll take...
What is this one again?
Explosion.
Oh, I need a trigger for that one.
It's a static one.
This one may be better.
Three damage.
Five damage.
And it does slice damage.
So does this one.
But that's not gonna hit them.
Because it's melee.
I think I'm fine here.
I like it.
We're leaving.
And it's gonna have crit.
That's something.
Man, it's so weird that I levitate so fast.
That actually means we can get on top of the tree.
And grab the music wand.
Hey, that's for you.
Nice, the crit is already happening.
It's so awkward with the levitation though.
I'm not used to the speed of this levitation.
This is really gonna mess with me.
Oh!
Look at this!
Another foot!
Another Italy!
Oh no, am I in the exact same digging situation as last?
Hold on, hold on.
Maybe this one will dig.
Yeah, kind of!
Shit!
Why?
Oh, burning trail.
I should have read the instructions on the manual.
For the wand.
That was a rookie mistake.
Shit.
Oh, it's a...
Oh, this feels good actually.
Having acceleration and the faster levitation feels amazing.
Because it's not at a different x and y speed, you know?
It's the same.
And if I find the perk to get faster horizontal speed, I'll take it.
Just to alleviate this problem that I have right now.
And I'm gonna be fast as fuck.
That's nice.
I'm going straight to fungal caverns and you can't stop me.
There's riches to be found.
Okay, you really want to follow me?
Yes, you do.
Shit, shit, mana, mana, mana!
Oh, that was scary.
Shit!
I ran out of levitation.
Okay, we're fine, we're fine.
Now, how do I get in there?
God, I'm so painfully slow in the horizontal.
I'm horizontally challenged.
And vertically amplified.
I love that.
Let's grab this wand.
Charm on toxic sludge.
No.
Or wait up.
No, no, no.
1080.
The full HD wand.
Whoa.
I think I'm gonna have trouble getting to fungal caverns.
I need some reliable way of digging.
Is there really no way for me to get over there?
Hold on.
No.
Maybe here?
Come on.
Chainsaw!
Do your thing.
Okay, fuck it, I'm leaving.
We do have 1100 gold.
That's gonna purchase everything here.
Okay.
Nice.
Ooh.
Lots of chainsaws.
Glass cannon.
Hmm.
I'm kind of tempted.
But I've never tried breathless.
Maybe it's good.
I mean, I guess it's kind of cool.
Moving in liquids is also kind of useful.
I don't know.
Maybe I'll just re-roll.
Yes!
We're back!
I've got a second chance at life here.
Oh, I'm so glad I re-rolled that.
Goddamn.
Oh.
Very nice.
Now, do I want any of these ones specifically?
Hold on.
Why did I pick up this wand?
Because it was decent, I guess.
This is better.
Give me these bad boys.
Oh, yeah.
And the heavy spreads and that.
But hold on.
It was a shovel wand.
So we don't want it.
Oh, I need a trigger.
Do we have a trigger?
Come on.
No.
Oh, we do have the second best thing.
The chain bolt.
I will take that.
I don't need two lights, I don't think.
I do need a million chainsaws, though.
That is important.
I'll leave that up there.
I'll leave those there in a nice pile.
I think my main wand is going to be this one.
That's the best I've got.
And maybe with all the chainsaws, we can actually make something crazy happen.
How much do they cost?
One.
I want to put something else on here.
Maybe something like that.
How is that not faster?
Shouldn't that be much faster?
Have I not reduced it to zero?
Oh, wait a minute, this is even faster.
Wait, what?
Oh, okay, so there's a sweet spot.
Uh, all right.
But chain bolt, though, is much better.
I don't like this.
This is a shitty wand.
Chain bolt is the way to go.
Oh, but oh, this wand sucks, though.
That's not bad.
That's nice.
That's solid.
In fact, I had more chain bolts.
Did I not?
Was there only two?
I don't remember.
I think that was only two.
Okay, that's good.
Circle of shielding.
I'm not really using it.
I think I should use it.
I can definitely make something out of this.
Oh, yeah, look at that.
That's the digging wand.
Well, soft digging wand.
It's a soft dig.
It's not a hard dig.
I will never grow up.
That's it?
That is it?
Very...
Oh, actually.
Oh, that's way too fast, though.
I actually go oom with that.
That's better.
And we have plenty of chainsaw, so I can even throw this wand away if I want to.
Seems good to me.
Get the hell out of here.
So we're gonna have trouble dealing with mechanical enemies, for sure.
And now we need to find another bottle, as well.
I think for now, I may just convert my water bottle to blood, because that can also put out fires.
It's the better choice.
Ah, but hold on.
And look at this!
Chainsaws!
Yeah!
Your boy has not forgotten.
Let's just get rid of this water.
No, no, no, don't fill it up.
Stand here.
Ah!
Motherfucker jumped up!
And this guy shot me through the wall.
Wow, it's going great.
Good thing I can heal from their blood.
This is the sort of thing where I love to have vampirism.
Absolutely love it.
Give me vampirism.
I mean, give me blood.
Drink.
And the best part is, it's so good in the beginning, because you heal so fast.
In fact, usually I have it on this.
That's the power of vampirism.
It allows for fuck-ups, which I do a lot of.
And that's the thing that's going to carry me to the end.
Let
me get some more blood here.
Look at all that blood.
And full HP.
We are so back!
Just grab all the blood.
I'm starting to think maybe I should have multiple bottles of blood.
Why would I have a single?
When I could have multiple.
In fact, if I find one of those people throwing diagonal bottles, I mean, triangular bottles.
I'm going to grab them, because they contain the double the amount.
And you can make an insane bottle out of that.
Oh, that's an explosive.
What's happening here?
Didn't this water just spawn out of nowhere?
Call me crazy, but I feel like that's what just happened.
These little guys.
Yeah, is that all you got?
Puff of smoke.
Watch my chain bolt, though.
I can shoot through walls.
How about them apples?
Damn, that is a lot of puff of smoke.
I will not take it.
Therefore, I will puff puff pass it.
I feel so weird not walking fast horizontally when I'm vertically amplified.
I really dislike that feeling.
I got to find acceleration or something.
Diggity dick.
I'm hella slick.
Oh, actually, I'm not very slick at all.
Get back.
What's that?
It's meat.
That means blood for me.
Even though it was rotten, kind of nasty.
I don't care.
I'll eat it.
I'll do what it takes.
I am not fire immune.
Oh, there's actually dangerous.
I can't deal with mechanical enemies.
Just don't have the firepower.
I mean, maybe I do.
If I can hide behind a wall like this, then I'm all for it.
Nice.
Rock spirits.
Uh, no.
Dude, imagine if I took the gamble and I got taken with once out of it.
And fire resistance.
Oh, my God.
Oh, no, what's happening?
Oh, no, the gods are going to get angry.
It's over.
Shit.
In fact, the best defense I have against them is this.
The chainsaw.
Drink, drink, drink, drink, drink.
He died?
No, wait, wait, wait.
No, that's ice.
Oh, no.
Stuart, are you here?
Oh, no, wait.
I haven't gotten the message yet.
I think we're fine right now.
I like the timer there.
What's this?
Fate.
Ooh, yes.
Don't mind if I do.
Oh, but wait.
Okay, thank God.
It's only me who bleeds flammable oil.
If it was everyone, I may have just killed my run because of amperism.
But we're fine.
Everything's okay.
I like that.
I like this.
The rest.
Not so much.
Actually, I am immune to fire.
And I...
Ooh, hold on.
Should we go nuts with the fire?
How about we do this?
Timer, quadruple.
We're gonna cut quadruple chainsaw people.
Maybe we add a little bit of something else.
Maybe an explosion on top of it.
Or fire.
Flaming chainsaws.
How about them apples?
It's not bad.
And it's kind of fast as well.
This does cost five mana, though.
That will...
Oh, also notice how the chainsaw activates here.
Because it's a timer.
So I can't be shooting from too far away.
That's gonna release fire like that.
But if I put it here...
Yeah, that's kind of sketchy.
That seems cooler, though.
But it is gonna potentially blow up things near me.
I guess.
I could also throw an explosion in there.
80 mana drain.
Nah.
Too much mana.
I like that.
We could do this, actually.
Oh, it's not actually helping much.
So, wait, 0.52.
This adds 0.05.
Okay.
I think I need something like light.
Let me see here.
Four, one, two, three...
No, no, actually, this is gonna...
Hold on.
Yeah, yeah, this should work.
Yeah, you see that?
We get an extra chainsaw in the beginning.
What double did they be doing?
But it doesn't feel faster.
Honestly, this feels faster.
This feels slower.
What the hell?
Yeah, that doesn't do anything, either.
Yeah, I don't know.
That's too much mana.
I think this is fine.
Keep it simple.
I'm not sure if it's better than the chain bolts.
That's gotta be.
Circle of shielding.
I may just put it up here.
Oh, no.
Look at this.
The worm is almost here.
That's really bad news.
Okay, I'm doing average damage, I want to say.
And I'm immune to fire, so great.
Actually, being immune to fire here is a lesson.
And I'm gonna get all this blood.
Nice.
Very nice.
I actually have a decent setup for this.
The foundations are solid.
When I say foundation, it's pretty much the vampirism.
And all the chainsaws on my trigger is actually helping so much already, because it's making so much blood.
So I don't have to manually go in there and chainsaw afterwards.
Oh, you bastards!
See, stuff like this already healed.
Oh, wow,
the damage there.
I think that was a double explosion.
I forgot about this thing.
I activated that a million years ago, and it was just sitting there going, and then suddenly, boom.
Scary stuff.
That guy's a one.
Oh, that's scary.
I'm in danger.
Don't come up here.
Oh, eat from the blood.
Eat from the blood.
He killed himself.
Thank God.
Nobody else here.
You're here.
I'm just going to pick that up.
Okay, you can't be handling those things.
That is just not okay.
Don't you fucking...
Oh, my God.
This is something else.
Thank vampirism.
This would definitely have been the end of me.
S-tier perk.
Now you understand why I consider it S-tier.
I'm playing this as if I have 300 HP and I don't.
I really need to calm down.
In fact, it is kind of unusual to be here with this little HP.
Give me all the blood.
Very nice.
Uh-oh.
Give me all the blood.
There we go.
And we're ready.
Let's find some wands in here.
Let's find some actual spells.
Oh, that was a friendo.
Not that I needed actually.
Yeah, fuck the friendos.
We don't need to be befriending anyone.
Why would you befriend them when you can eat them or drink them?
That's what I say.
Bop!
I love bobbing people.
Look at all that blood.
This is my paradise.
Oh wait, that's not...
It's toxic!
It's gonna get turned into water though.
It's fine, it's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
Everything's fine.
Oh, except I'm drowning.
I'm not.
I'm just kidding.
Hey, sir.
Oh, that's electric.
Get me up.
Ah, here we go.
And I do have enough digging for this.
True orbit.
Summon platform.
No, I thought this was long distance cast.
I looked at the...
Ah, it looks exactly like it.
Dang it.
It's fine.
I'm gonna dig.
Oh, that's gonna take a while.
Kind of.
Do kind of want to find the teleportation first.
Maybe I'll come...
You know what?
I'm gonna come back here at the end of the level.
Maybe I'll have more digging by then.
And maybe I'll have teleportation.
Oh my god, he shoots missiles.
Ow!
Good thing I brought painkillers.
Just get in there.
Go through here.
Lovely.
Thank you.
Get some more blood.
See, this is solid.
Really need some kind of mana on this wand.
I see electricity.
Oh, shit, I'm stuck.
I'm stuck, I'm stuck.
Yeah, I'm stuck!
Kill him quick.
Shit.
Oh, nice, nice, nice, nice, nice.
Oh man, good thing I'm immune to fire, huh?
That was way too risky.
Otherwise...
I mean, if I wasn't immune to fire, I would never have gone down there.
You know me.
I don't take risks.
Teleportation!
Well, well, well.
That's exactly what I need.
Sayonara!
I'm going back to the shop.
I really want to find a teleport spell, actually.
It's about time.
Wait, where did I access?
Is it up there?
Yeah, it must have been because it's dark down here.
Yeah, here we go.
Now, the digging is not great.
But it works.
In a pinch.
Now, I just need to not break the glass like that one time.
Where everything fell down on me and I died.
I got to put that on the in the death compilation, actually.
In fact, I got to put everything in the death compilation.
I kind of forgot what was in here, actually.
Like a portal opened and I forgot what happened after.
It's all a blur.
Let me through.
What the fuck?
OK, there's a little piece of something there.
Here we are.
Gently, gently.
Now, I do love how this liquid looks, you know.
Polymorphism and teleportation, unstable, all of it looks.
Oh, there we go.
Oh, that's right.
I remember now.
Nuke orbit.
I'll take it.
Oh, wait, they're free.
Oh, my God.
Nice.
What's that?
Null shot.
I mean, if it's free, I'll just take all of it, I guess.
Explode.
Sure.
Nah, explosion is bad.
I'm not immune to that.
I don't want it.
Spitter bolt with timer.
I like it.
What's that one?
Large spitter bolt with timer.
I am intrigued by nuke orbit, honestly.
That sounds like a suicide thing.
Look at that one.
Let's take rotate towards foes.
Now I wonder, what if I fill it with blood now?
What happens then?
Can I double dibby-do?
Maybe I need to get out the...
I probably need to empty it first of unstable teleportation.
I don't know how to do that, though.
That seems impossible.
I can't squeeze.
Can I squeeze through that?
Hold on.
Yeah.
Nope.
I can't.
I could...
If I had a long distance teleport, I could maybe get in there, but it would have to be done correctly, because even the teleport spell will break that glass.
I've had experience with that.
It's not pretty.
But that's nice.
We got a mix for nukes?
Rotate around a projectile.
I love how the developers admit that it's a little bit insane.
Even they know that it's nuts, you know?
That's fun.
I need more blood.
Nice.
And we're back.
Back in the mix.
With all the tricks.
Still not able to dicks.
Dig.
I mean, we got the chainsaw, but is that really digging?
I would say it's not.
I'm definitely not leaving yet.
So there is actually one issue here.
Something I need to solve in this game, which is...
Can I get...
Actually, hold on.
I know the answer to this question, but let me post it anyway.
Just so you know what I'm thinking.
Is there a way to get back to the surface without ever angering the gods?
And I think the answer is yes, there is.
Through the tower.
I realized that while thinking about it just now.
Ah, that's electricity!
Oh, wait.
It was fine.
But I need to get back up again, and I need some way to get back up again, and down, up, up, up, down, up, down, up, down.
All the time.
Without angering the gods.
If I find peace with gods, I'm taking that instantly.
Dude, if I find peace with gods and take it with wands, I think I'm taking peace with gods.
That's how fucking terrified I am of Stuart.
I don't care.
You can't take it with shit if you're dead.
Nice.
We need hearts badly.
Oh,
shit.
That was a little bit too risky, though.
Let's just get that blood back.
Another heart!
Oh, that's huge.
That's so big, actually.
Hello.
Nice.
I handled that perfectly.
What if I kick this guy?
What, what, what then?
I'm too slippery!
No, no!
Wrong bottle!
Oh, we're fine, we're fine.
Why do I overreact so much?
It's... I don't know, man, it is...
It is what it is.
It's like...
The game is PTSD inducing, okay?
Like, you've seen some of those stuff, like, wherever you get teleported, you know shit's about to go down, you know?
Uh, that's chaotic polymorphism.
Like, there was one time I got teleported straight into lava and I died immediately.
So, yeah.
Being scared makes sense.
Okay, back on top, full health, full blood.
There's only one thing men want.
And it's fucking bloody.
Oh, nice, look at that.
Oh, this is gonna take a while.
The tough snow there.
It's the best I've got.
Ah, let me go through somewhere else.
Kivaskivi.
I'm gonna take that, why not?
I'm immune to fire.
Man, I'm kind of locked in here.
I guess I'll do some digging then.
I have no choice.
Oh no, a terrible place to dig.
I guess I keep digging over here, it's fine.
Just go.
So many friendos.
Feels like a waste, you know?
My goodness, these guys again.
Immediately, they just hit me.
Fuck off.
You should not be the end of me this time.
I will fucking chainsaw all of you.
I saw my own death there.
I just saw myself in the blood and I saw the electricity.
That was scary.
Why are there so many of these easy people?
Take it easy, man.
Look at all this blood.
This is from all the people I've murdered.
Isn't that glorious?
It's a vampire's wet dream, actually.
Oh yeah.
Energy orb.
I'll take it.
Oh, that's fun.
Okay, man, I think heezy base is my favorite area.
It's just so dense, filled with goodies.
Cool enemies.
Oh my god, please die.
What the hell?
Okay, there we go.
Let's just make some more blood.
How does...
How do they have all that fucking blood in their bodies?
That's way too much blood.
That ain't right.
Yay!
More HP.
Dude, heezy base has been good to me.
This has been a turning point in this run for sure.
Oh, beep.
Come here.
Maybe I'm doing a little bit crazy things here.
I may...
Let's get the hell out.
Oh no.
I'm in a bad spot.
Okay, calm down.
What am I doing?
It's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
Everything's fine.
Just chillax.
Destroy them with the box.
Nice.
I'm starting to get the overconfident again.
This is a bad sign.
Ouch.
We're gonna produce lots of blood from these people.
I just pop out and shoot and back down again.
Ah, it's fun.
That is amazing.
Nice.
Let's just make some more blood here.
Oh, yeah.
And now we heal up.
Dude, fire resistance and vampirism, name a better combo.
I dare you.
Okay.
I found a lot of hearts already.
But how about more hearts?
I don't want to be greedy or anything, but maybe?
Just a bit.
A couple hearts for me.
Actually, hold on, I can dig with this.
I gotta be careful though.
Sometimes there's explosives in the snow.
What's up, friendo?
Nice.
Dude, going in close and personal like that seems to work.
I'm gonna take your blood.
Nice.
I'm cleansing the base.
Man, I need a horizontal amplification.
Real bad.
Shit.
Is it time to leave, maybe?
I mean, if we leave, it's hard to come back.
Wait, why am I taking damage?
Oh, we had a bit of freezing vapor, I see.
I want to go more to the left.
All the way to the east.
West.
Oh, wait, that's toxic sludge.
I don't want to mess with that.
Hehehe.
Don't mess with me, bruh.
Uh, I think I'm gonna go below and then up.
But I came from here, so...
There's gotta be something here.
I'm gonna go...
Ah, it's gonna get turned into water, right?
We're totally fine here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No problem.
Oh, shit.
Dang.
As soon as we have a way of digging up, all the way to the top again.
I think it's fine to go do some exploration.
Like I said, we're not gonna get uber OP here.
We're just gonna get decent.
And right now, that feels...
Although, having teleport is a big boon.
We should probably try and find that first.
That is pretty much a must.
Either that or horizontal amplification.
Just something where we can travel it a bit faster.
These guys are born!
Oh!
Calm down, calm down.
Drink.
Get him.
Nice.
Now we leave.
Find some blood.
That was scary.
I think he had some kind of ex...
I don't even know.
Electrical explosion thingy on him.
Lightning bolt.
That's how fast I'm going.
From 0 to 100.
Or in this case, from 100 to almost 0.
Here we go.
More.
Ah, that's some here.
Ooh!
Look at that!
I'm actually happy all of this happened then.
That is so lucky.
Yeah!
Look, when they're too far away, I'm not doing that much damage to them.
Because the timer runs out before the impact.
I think I forgot about that for a while.
So I may have done very little damage without knowing it or realizing.
God, the chainsaw combination with vampirism is actually the best.
So good.
Cool.
I found, like, what, four or five hearts in this place?
This has been incredible.
Another one!
And another one.
And another...
Oh, god.
I forgot who that is.
Well, there's a meme with that.
Some kind of singer.
Is it DJ?
What's his name?
Fuck, I forgot.
Yeah, look, he had a thunder charge.
That bastard.
Was it DJ Khaled or something?
And another one.
I'm a simple man.
I enjoy simple things.
What's up, people?
It is I, the chainsaw man.
I've come to chain your saw.
So satisfying.
This is what I mean.
Like, I have a shit...
Let's be honest here.
This one, it's kind of shitty.
But vampirism makes it okay.
Doesn't matter.
Okay, that's actually a bit scary, what I'm doing there.
Don't do that.
Oh, don't do that either!
I'm doing dumb dumb things here.
Why am I taking damage?
Oh, was I actually polishing still?
No!
Fuck!
Oh.
Dude!
That is a genius way, actually.
I completely forgot about this.
I need to use that to get into the holy mountain.
Oh, but wait, wait, wait, no!
It's unstable!
I can't use this.
No, no, no, I'm fine.
I'm totally fine.
I'm okay.
I didn't forget anything here.
It was unstable.
Couldn't have used it anyway.
But if I find normal teleportation, I can angle it.
Aim it.
Bend it to my will, as they say, in something.
Give me blood.
Good.
Now, who wants to play catch?
I'm gonna make a hole here.
Excuse me, sir.
That's for you!
Yeah!
Wow, that did almost nothing.
Kivaskivi, kind of useless, confirmed?
246 HP.
I came in here with a hundred something.
A hundred and ten, maybe.
Nah, maybe not that low, but it was very low.
Oh, oh!
My dude has a wand.
Got him.
Let me just...
Oh, nice!
A reduced recharge.
That is fantastic news.
Very good.
Nothing like a cleansing fire.
Am I glad I'm immune to fire?
You know?
Oh, I don't even consider it a downside to bleed oil.
Maybe a little bit.
I'm actually way too close to those explosives, especially when they're on fire.
That is something I need to not do.
I think I've done enough here.
I'm leaving.
Yeah, I'm doing great.
Am I...
Oh, I'm poisoned.
Oh, shit!
Ah, well, that sucks.
Oh, ingesting oil.
Oh, did I have oil in my...
I must have had oil in there.
That's bad.
Ooh.
Always casts a yellow glimmer.
Ooh, we've got a tele...
Oh, there we go.
The teleport.
Oh, lovely.
Exactly what I need.
I'm not enthused by any of this.
All of this is pretty much boo.
Ah!
You're immune to electric damage.
But metal and liquids around you electrify constantly.
I am kind of wanting to take that.
I want to take that.
I'm taking that.
It's going to be maybe annoying to witness.
But it is what it is.
Okay.
I definitely want this one.
That's for sure.
Oh, before I take it.
This is a shitty wand.
It's...
Nope.
Give it to that one.
Put this one up here.
This one can go away.
Now get that.
I do like this, I guess.
Ah, I don't need this anymore.
We don't need multiple of these.
That's nice.
What else do we got?
Actually, this is a decent wand.
Not a lot of slots though, but it's definitely something I can work with.
We'll make this better for sure.
Let's grab that.
Oh, hold on.
Yeah.
Just get it.
Triplicate.
Oh, you know what's great about this?
I'm going to be sawing up people creating huge blood pools, you know?
Swimming in there.
Electrifying everything.
Enemies are going to come chasing me and they're going to get electrified and stunned.
It's awesome.
I mean, it looks scary when you see it like that, but...
It's not scary at all, it's fine.
Spark Bowl with Timer is 10, 30, 45.
This one had 53 mana charge.
I'm actually so happy about this.
I'm going to be able to charge so much quicker.
Let's just see the difference.
Still feels kind of slow.
How is that possible?
What is adding...
Wait a minute.
How is that not a zero...
Oh, cast delay.
It's the cast delay.
That actually adds 0.05, so we have 0.15 cast delay in total.
I see.
So we got a red...
Oh, we do have this though.
Hey, there it is.
Yeah, there it is.
Holy shit.
God damn, that was fast.
We need mana.
Oh, fishies!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry about that.
I'm just going to take a...
I'm just going to confirm something here.
Okay, I don't get stunned.
Everything's great.
Because if I got stunned right now there and not take damage, I would restart the whole run immediately.
That would have been terrible.
I wonder if there's a way to respect in the game actually, now that I think about it.
Who knows?
Maybe there's a perk or something in the world that will allow you to remove a perk, you know?
A cleansing perk or something.
Okay.
Is this the wand that I want to run with?
Probably not, right?
It's actually way too fast.
I would like something that is fast, but not too fast.
Otherwise, I run out of mana.
This does cast delay.
Man, I feel like I should be able to make something out of this.
Like, I have so much here.
Hold on, let me see the other ones.
360...
480...
These ones all suck.
This is a shitty wand.
I mean, I can make it fast, but...
I have to wait, you know, that's...
It is a lot of damage, but it's not good enough.
That's just not good at all.
Wow, that's fast on its...
Wait, what?
Wow, is that...
It's the cast delay?
Oh, it reduces cast delay, this one.
Interesting.
Huh!
Oh, that's fun.
All right.
Maybe we have too much of this, then?
Nice.
It does cost too much mana, I think.
I need to find...
So, here's the thing.
The wand is already fast.
We don't need to do something crazy here.
I need a simple spark bolt with trigger, man.
That's what I need.
Although this is the same mana cost.
Using the...
Or is it that one?
I think it's spark bolt with trigger is also 10 mana drain, isn't it?
So, maybe it's not a big difference.
Did that...
That did cost a mana.
Triple scatter.
Didn't we find a double cast or something somewhere?
That cost zero, I believe.
Did I throw it down here?
Hmm.
I don't like my wands.
In fact, this is too fast.
It sounds dumb, but...
The wand is too fast.
Let's put...
Let's try something else.
This is a little bit slower, but then again, the mana recharge is also half of what this wand is.
If I add nothing...
See, that's about the speed I want.
Maybe a little faster.
Yeah, add a bit more to that.
Let's add something like...
I don't even know.
What do we have?
Something damage.
What's that?
Chaotic path?
More projectile speed?
No.
Slime mist.
Fuck, I don't know.
Oh, hold on.
Ah, this is shuffle.
Shit.
That's not great.
I mean, this is fine.
That is fine.
And it is a better wand in the end.
I'll just take that.
That's okay.
We'll make something better later.
I think I still want to keep...
No, the chainsaws, actually.
I want to switch.
This does make blood.
Let's not forget.
We can grab some of these to do some digging.
Right.
And we can get rid of something up here.
That one.
I don't really like that.
Because I don't understand it.
And when I don't understand something, then I dislike it.
Just kidding.
Ah, let's see how that looks.
Actually, this is a...
timer, so a bit annoying.
That's too slow.
Oh, that one's fast, actually.
Not bad, but oh, look at the mana charge speed.
Yikes.
We can't do that.
I think this is it.
Teleport.
That one.
And unfortunately, we have no digging bolt or something.
That would be great.
I think we're fine.
Let's go.
Right.
Everything is cool.
Nothing else.
We are healed up.
Practically.
No blood.
Gotta find that.
Unstable teleportation.
Not so great, though.
We gotta get that taken care of.
I kind of forgot how much more HP these guys have in the jungle.
Also, I need to train my mind not to be scared of the electricity.
I'm gonna see it everywhere and have PTSD, you know?
I bet you there's something great in here, though.
This is where I'll find it.
Levitation.
I wonder how fast that's gonna be now.
It's the same.
It doesn't add.
I need to find blood, actually.
Oh, shit.
Someone hit me really nice there.
I hate these guys so much.
It's the blood I need.
Give me blood.
Oh, man, the blood is too scattered.
Hard to pick up.
Ah, here we go.
Oh, what the fuck that scared me!
Oh, my heart!
God damn it.
Wait, I'm actually gonna die here.
Got him.
Okay.
Okay, this is...
I kind of regret taking the electricity bullshit.
It's very confusing.
You keep thinking everything is gonna go bad.
All the time.
God, this one sucks.
Uh, I don't know why I just fell all the way down.
I need to find a proper spot where I can feed on some blood.
Are you kidding me?
Why did that just explode?
Wait, is it the electricity?
Oh, no!
Am I forever?
Oh, no, I may have made a big mistake taking the electricity.
I'm dying, I'm dying here.
I have to abort.
Let's not forget that.
Kill him, kill him, kill him.
Okay, emergency, emergency.
Get some blood, get some blood.
Drink.
Ah, it's so scattered.
Okay, we're healing slowly.
I need to find a kill room with a nice big bath where I can fill it up with blood.
Don't put me on a list.
Back up, back up, back up.
We're not going further down.
So, I think my electricity is definitely triggering bombs around me, which is horrible news.
Did not consider that.
Actually, I have no idea that that would happen like that.
So, but here we go.
We got some blood.
Oh, yeah, plenty of blood, plenty of blood.
That's what I'm talking about.
We're feasting.
Things got a little bit hairy back there.
We have recovered.
We are a-okay.
Gotta up that HP pool.
Dude, I just realized I haven't taken a single fucking break today.
And my whole plan was to take a break every hour.
Why am I so terrible with this?
Sorry, I was drinking.
Come on, man.
Can you have some respect here?
I hate when my screen goes red.
Makes me think I'm about to die.
Like someone walking up to you, taking you by the shoulders and shaking you going, you're okay!
I'm like, okay, all right, all right, fine.
Don't have to scream at me.
I get it.
Sir, stop that.
Okay.
All right, here's the thing.
Things are looking solid right now.
We have everything set up, sort of.
We have a shitty wand, but it's okay.
We have vampirism.
That's great.
We are immune to fire.
Great.
Immune to electricity.
Amazing.
I'll stop it here.
Because I gotta take a break and I gotta stop for today.
But I want to end on a good note here.
I don't want to die and then end, you know?
That's the worst feeling.
So I have something to look forward to next time.
Okay.
Oh, man.
The whole plan was to take a break every hour.
So I should have had five breaks this stream and I had zero.
Isn't that just incredible?
Next time, I'm gonna put a timer on my phone.
I did that the last time as well, but I forgot to set it up again afterwards.
Classic, huh?
How's everybody doing?
Very big spoiler above?
Gotcha.
I'm not gonna check.
Don't worry.
All good.
GG's, indeed.
Indeed.
Oh, hard procession has raided.
Two hours ago.
Thank you for that.
I don't know if you're here, hard procession.
How do I do the shout-out thing?
People always give me a shout-out when I raid and I don't know how they do it.
I'm gonna shout you out.
Wait.
There's nothing on his...
name.
Maybe just do slash...
shout-out.
Oh, yeah, that works.
Hard.
Thanks, man.
No, you just did?
Yeah, I mean, like, officially.
So you can do something like this.
That's what I mean.
Because I can see that in my activity feed when someone did that last time to me.
Yeah, exactly.
Thank you, hard procession.
I don't know if you're still here.
Probably not.
Or if you ever were.
I appreciate it.
Is anyone from that stream still here at all?
You're doing well, Cheson.
Besides dying on a nine-hour god run in the morning.
Oh, no!
How did you die?
If you don't mind telling.
So you were just a demigod this time around, I guess.
Hard procession has been speedrunning.
Oh, fuck.
Dude, I can't even imagine speedrunning Noita.
Shit.
Oh, you died so redacted, gotcha.
Okay.
Say no more, fam.
I know exactly what that means, wink wink.
Technically, I guess I am.
Wait, what did I ask before?
Oh, still here from the raid.
Okay, yeah.
Red X sweaters.
Speedrun is actually easier unless you're going for records.
Really?
I guess when you say speedrun, you mean kill the last boss, right?
And get a win.
Or I imagine there's different categories just like every other game when it comes to speedrunning.
I died to redacted ones, what a bummer.
I know, right?
But redacted is such an asshole.
Oh, Huguenomikron already made that joke.
Fuck.
I read it right after, I swear.
Dammit.
Oh, yeah.
He really is.
What's up, Lexi?
How you doing?
On this beautiful Wednesday.
Did you all vote for the next game, by the way?
I put a poll up for the next offline game.
Actually, I gotta check that.
What is winning right now?
I think last time I checked, it was Stanley Parable.
Oh, yeah, Stanley Parable is winning hard.
Followed by Bioshock and Little Nightmares.
Damn.
You guys really wanna see Stanley Parable, huh?
Yeah, I think there's no way any other game is gonna overtake now.
Stanley Parable has won for sure.
With 12, almost 13,000 points, damn.
Compared to the second most, 9,400.
That's a clear lead.
It'll be a video series, Huguenomikron.
Looking forward to it?
Yeah, man, for sure.
I mean, I don't really know what it's about, but I'm excited to check it out.
It's always a nice feeling to check out a new game.
You finished Pacific Drive a couple weeks ago.
I heard it's really good.
I heard it has a great atmosphere, and that's something I...
That's one of the reasons I put it on the list as well.
The word of mouth is powerful.
It's a parable.
So, correct me if I'm wrong, but in English, a parable, isn't that the same thing as a story?
So, like, the Stanley story or something?
The Stanley myth?
Something like that?
You know, like, the parables of old.
I always have that saying in my head for some reason, and it means, like, the stories of old, right?
But yeah, I'm looking forward to it.
In fact, I can't wait to play...
I have way too little time and too many games.
I've said that before, but it's true.
I want to play...
Oh, by the way, the reason I put Alan Wake on there and not...
So, I know that Alan Wake is connected to Control in some way, and people on the Discord were saying that I should play Alan Wake before playing Control.
So, apparently, that's the first game that company made, and then they made Alan Wake 2, and then they made Control, right?
And those games are amazing, apparently, so...
Parable is a type of story that teaches a lesson.
Oh, wow, I see!
Oh, that's actually nice to know.
A story with a...
With a point.
With a lesson, yeah, okay.
Or a morale or something, what do you call it?
It's just the same universe?
I think you can play them in any order.
Oh, okay!
I was under the assumption that you needed to play the Alan Wake one first.
I have returned.
What are we talking...
We're talking about whether or not to play Alan Wake before any of the other games in that universe.
And also, we're talking about how Stanley Parable is winning the poll.
It's winning by a lot, so I think it's going to be Stanley Parable.
That one is pretty much locked in.
Hubris Plus, is that the official release order, or is it the order that...
Because I would rather play it in the official release order, I think.
Unless it's, like, one of those...
You know how Star Wars has, like, six movies?
And technically, four, five, or like one, two, and three happened later.
And people were like, oh, chronologically, you should watch four, five, or one, two, and three first, and then four, five, and six...
Wait, hold on, I'm confusing here.
You know what I mean.
I'm confusing everything.
But it's the release order, right?
You want a horror game?
Yeah, me too, man.
I actually, I'm starting to like horror games more lately.
It is, it is, like, I get frightened so easily, but it is a lot of fun.
I do enjoy it a lot.
I have fond memories of playing Amnesia, the Dark Descent.
That shit scarred me, man.
I think once a year I go in and watch day nine play Amnesia, the Dark Descent.
That is one of the funniest things on the internet.
If you haven't seen the highlights from his playthrough of Amnesia, it's the best.
It's so funny.
The first Amnesia.
Horror games make me actually scream.
Me too, man.
Me too.
One of my friends, Peter.
He never gets affected by any horror ever.
It's insane.
I don't understand it.
I did play Soma, yes, Narivan.
Soma was incredible.
And scary.
Actually, the reason I played Soma was because I figured out it was the same developers that made Amnesia.
And it was sci-fi, so I thought, damn, this is gonna be good.
I lied, exactly!
I lied 33.
That's where I heard it too.
Good Will Hunting.
He's standing in front of the glass with the girl's number on it.
On the piece of paper, right?
My name is also Peter, but I get very spooked.
Easily jumpscared.
Yeah, it's just this one friend Peter I have that is immune to it, apparently.
Like, I don't understand how that's even possible.
I'm the same way in real life.
If someone stands behind a door and waits for me and jumps out, I fucking die.
I can't.
Soma, Amnesia, all other Amnesia games.
Soma is definitely something else, isn't it?
I don't wanna say too much about it, because it is such a great game when it comes to story and reveals and all that, so yeah.
If you haven't played Soma, and you are able to stomach some horror, I definitely recommend Soma.
It's so good.
Really makes you think.
Are there any other games that are not in my backlog right now?
If you guys have even checked that out, that you think I should put on there?
Because the bigger...
So the way I do this, whenever it's time to play a new game, I basically open my backlog, and I look through everything and I pick 10 games that I feel like playing in that moment.
That sounds interesting, you know?
So the bigger the backlog, I guess the more watered out it is a little bit, but also there's a chance to get that game in the rotation.
Yeah, I'm gonna send you a link to the backlog.
There's no command for that.
Maybe I should do it, actually.
That's not a bad idea.
There you go.
You like sandbox building games?
You mean like Minecraft?
That's a sandbox building game, right?
But if it's just about building and that's it, probably not.
There's gotta be some kind of element to it that drives me or motivates me.
Oh, Factorio!
I've played some of Factorio.
I've played like 10 hours of it or something.
And I've played a little bit of it with a friend too, for like a couple hours.
Really fun.
Very addicting.
I think you guys would get an aneurysm watching me play that.
But honestly, at the moment, I'm still intrigued to play more of it, but I'm waiting until they release the...
They have some kind of big DLC coming or big expansion to the game that will change almost everything.
So I'm looking forward to that.
I have a friend who wants to recommend a Minecraft adventure map, if you'd be interested in that.
Dreamall is the map, it seems cool from what I've seen.
Is that the same idea as when Oobshie made that map for me?
In the Minecraft wrap-up streams?
Is that what you mean when you say adventure maps?
Yeah, I heard Satisfactory also just came out in 1.0.
Also a similar game to Factorio, but in 3D.
It's on my backlog as well.
Oh, not exactly.
It's a map with its own lore and stuff.
Oh, interesting.
But it's made within Minecraft.
It's not a separate game, right?
It's just a server, so to speak.
Caves of Kut, or Kut, I don't know how to pronounce that.
Let me see here.
Like, I've never heard of this game.
The fact that you guys are just throwing out games there that I've never even heard of, and I consider myself quite, you know, knowledgeable in the world of games.
Just, there's so many games, it's crazy.
But it sounds awesome.
Assigned, fantasy, roguelike, epic, steeped in retrofuturism.
Damn.
Sounds cool.
I'm gonna put it on the backlog.
There it is.
Thanks for that suggestion.
There's no search option in the backlog.
That's an oversight.
That should definitely be a thing, I feel.
I mean, on that website.
It's a world you can download and just explore and adventure.
People make lots of cool adventure and puzzle maps.
Ah, I see.
I mean, I want to say yes, obviously.
If it's cool, then I want to do it.
Oh, what's this?
Kobe.
A raider.
Caves of Koot upvote.
Oh, did you also raid me?
I didn't even notice Kobe.
Thank you.
Yeah, it's on the list right now.
I didn't raid you.
It says to me, you're a raider.
Like, your name is highlighted and all.
I'm still trying to understand the Twitch interface here, I'm not gonna lie.
It's all a little bit confusing.
By the way, guys, I'm starting to send the little hamster with the fan in the background spinning to my friends on every messaging app now.
I use it all the time.
I'm addicted to that little fucking hamster.
I don't know why everyone's posting that hamster.
I see it all the time.
What's with the hamster?
Is it maybe the reply highlight?
No, no, it says raider on my screen.
I don't know why.
But, uh...
Caves of Koot.
Yeah, it's on the list now, Kobe.
It is on the list.
It replaces lol?
Why?
Why does it do that?
Really?
I mean, I actually like that.
I thought the hamsters from when you're clueless.
That's what I think too.
I mean, I look at that a hamster and it's just...
You know, I get the same energy from that hamster as that guy who eats chips.
You know, who sits there, stares into the camera, and eats chips from a bag.
Looks all serious, you know?
There's something...
It has the same energy.
Me watching you dip an ass.
I don't know what Walter Dog is.
Hold on, what is that?
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
Or like those images your parents or grandparents take of themselves with a new smartphone.
Where their face is all close to the camera, they don't know how to angle themselves, you know?
That's the funniest shit.
Exactly lol me that one.
I love that...
Where's that even from, man?
I love the internet.
It's too good.
Why is he sitting there eating from that bag, you know?
I wonder what the equivalent for grandkids will be.
I don't know, I'm starting to feel a little old, you know, when you guys are helping me with technical things.
I consider myself a technical person, you know?
But like when I had Jen help me out with set up the mods for Minecraft and all that, I felt like an old person, you know?
Oh, tell me how to do it.
I mean, they were very willing to help me, so...
Yeah, I do.
But yeah, I've never done it like done anything in Minecraft, though.
I don't know what kind of language they use for there.
I mean, I pretty much exclusively use Python in my in my professional job.
I know a little bit of some other languages, but it's not something that I use mainly.
There are more emotes I want to suggest.
Maybe one day I will post in Discord.
Yes, please do.
Please.
If it's part of the whole 7TV or whatever it's called...
Is it called 7TV?
I think it is.
7TV, then just put it in there and I'll throw in some more emotes.
Also, there's a bunch of emote slots on Twitch because of all the people subscribing.
I have so many empty emote slots.
I don't know what to put in there, guys.
Please, if you have suggestions or something, I will gladly fill it up with all the emotes that we need.
We can put in more animated emotes, too.
I already played some Civilization.
I played Civilization 5.
It was good.
Definitely a great game to chill with late night.
You know, the classic One More Turn definitely rings true for that.
And there's a new Civilization coming.
Soundboard slots?
Oh, you mean on Discord?
Hell yeah.
We should make some soundboards.
That would be great.
People make emotes related to games they play, but you play variety, yeah.
But I guess...
So, the Hymnus dancing is actually funny, you know?
I feel like that can be funny even when you're not playing Noiter.
Or like the emotes that Crowwater made, such as the Boing one for the music.
Those can be universal across games.
I like that you guys are memeing so much about the status card thing.
I actually...
I'm embarrassed I didn't notice that earlier.
Goddamn.
How long were you guys molding about that?
I don't even know how long I didn't notice.
But it was quite a while, right?
I thought for sure a status card was like a card that would pop up later in the game.
That I haven't unlocked yet, or on the latest character or something like that.
I never noticed it actually set status on those grey fucking cards.
The Kiva Skivi?
Oh yeah.
I would say more like Uku Skivi would be an appropriate emote to have.
That one causes way more trouble than the Kiva Skivi, though.
Lolvi, is that from...
Oh, what's this guy's name?
Forsen.
The emote.
That's the Forsen face.
I'm easily entertained by these emotes.
We need more of them, definitely.
By the way, guys, regarding Noita, I think soon-ish.
Who knows, maybe next time.
Maybe not next time.
But I kind of want to start playing Noita while talking to you guys a little bit.
Because I feel like I've reached the point in the game where I've done a lot.
Obviously, there's still things to discover and things to figure out.
I'm not saying anyone is allowed to spoil or anything, but just talking while playing.
You know, just chilling a little bit.
Just a relaxed Noita stream, you know?
And maybe even have a wrap-up at some point for Noita.
The thing about wrap-up streams is that when we do them, it's kind of...
That's it, you know?
It's like revealing the magic trick and then the trick is no longer fun anymore.
In the way that if I ever decide to play it again in the future, figuring out some of the stuff that would be revealed is not going to be available to me.
You know?
But it would be fun, for sure.
But we could definitely have a stream where I just play and we can talk without spoiling, you know?
I mean, people are definitely able to do that.
I saw that for myself in Minecraft.
People were so nice with the spoilers.
If you remember, the very first stream of Minecraft...
I was looking at chat, but I was trying not to talk too much with chat.
But I was mostly reading what people were saying, right?
I would say like 20% of the time I was reading chat in the very first stream.
And then I decided from then on not to read chat at all.
And it worked fine.
People were not spoiling anything.
People were super nice.
So I think it can work.
Just have it in the title, you know?
No spoilers please or something or no backseat gaming.
There's no need to spoil anything to you except proper wand building and a couple tricks.
Nice.
Yeah, I'm still trying to nail the whole wand building.
I'm definitely missing some pieces.
And I think I also have an Achilles heel.
One of my issues is that I...
I'm unwilling to try new spells because they don't sound good on paper when I read them.
So I will never really try out potential amazing combinations.
For example, I'm definitely aware that I'm missing some of that stuff.
Hey, Reeve.
Yeah, I just finished.
It's been a long stream.
We did some neuter.
We're just chatting now.
How you doing?
You're reading chat while playing is fun.
It made the Starcraft stream so fun.
Yeah, so I don't actually play Starcraft that much anymore.
I have faces with Starcraft.
I played like a lot for maybe a couple months and then I stopped for a year or two.
Then I come back and played a lot for a couple months.
I go nuts with that.
But lately I'm starting to think maybe you should try Warcraft 3, you know?
Ladder.
And even the campaign.
I never finished the entirety of the campaign in Warcraft 3.
And it's been so long I honestly don't remember much of it.
So I think it could be super cool to just have a chill stream.
Chatting with you guys.
You know?
Playing some Warcraft.
Maybe learning to play Ladder.
I've been watching a lot of Grubby lately.
Playing Warcraft 3 on the Ladder.
And it's just so entertaining.
It seems like a great game.
Will the hardcore streams have chat on?
I don't think so.
I don't know yet.
I haven't decided.
But I'm definitely going to be playing as I've always played.
Just trying to beat the game, you know?
On hardcore.
That's my goal.
I want to just...
I want to beat the damn game.
I think it's going to be difficult.
Because now when I think about all the steps needed to beat the game.
It's kind of a lot, you know?
And I remember dying a lot in Minecraft.
And hardcore is even a higher difficulty than what I played back then.
I played on normal.
Hardcore will be until you die or beat the dragon.
Until I beat the dragon, of course.
That's the whole point.
No, no, no.
I'm going to go in there and teach him some manners.
No, it's a hardcore.
Damn.
Bro.
You do it.
That's insane.
Way too crazy.
Oh, nightmare.
Yeah, it's called nightmare, isn't it?
Or maybe he meant one death, the lead game.
Who knows?
And didn't you put more challenges on yourself?
I don't think so.
I think it's a big enough...
Honestly, I don't even know if I can do it.
When I think of all the steps required to reach the dragon and kill it.
And it's on a higher difficulty than what I did.
Holy shit.
That's not going to be easy.
I have no illusions about that.
No way.
I think it's going to be difficult for me.
What other games call hardcore is normal noiter.
I would say that's true.
You got to be ultra prepared to do anything.
Oh man, I am.
I am.
I'm actually also excited to try some of the things I never really dabbled much with in Minecraft.
For example, at the very end of Minecraft, I had the...
Remember, I built the pyramid thing.
That could give you buffs where you had to integrate.
I never really explored that very much.
And I think people explained it to me in the wrap up stream.
But I don't remember shit from that.
The beacon, exactly.
Stuff like that, you know?
Like, there's still things to do and discover in that game.
And I kind of want to do it.
Yeah, we're going to be frying some bacon.
It's going to be good.
You know, there's just some things...
And maybe, who knows?
Maybe there's even more things in the game I haven't discovered.
Biomes, I know I haven't discovered all of those.
There's a way in which hardcore Minecraft is easier.
You can always have all your best stuff with you at all times, since there is no issue with losing it due to dying.
Oh, but that's the whole point, no?
To start in with nothing but your bare hands and you have to punch a tree and somehow get to the end and murder the dragon without dying.
That's the challenge, right?
Hive, I may or may not already have been on the server, at times.
Seeing what you guys are up to.
Just saying.
Everything is not as it seems.
But yes, yes, I definitely want to come back also and check it out.
I lurk a little bit, yeah.
I have not, Hive.
I'm doing very basic things on the server.
I haven't played that much.
Just very little.
You're working on a mega project there.
Oh, shit.
I know people have been doing a lot on the server and you also had the whole anniversary event for the server, which was super cool.
I didn't join for that, but I heard about it.
And I saw you put out a video for it as well at some point.
I don't know how I saw that, but I saw it.
I didn't see the video, but I saw that you put it out and it looked like you guys had fun, so it's just so cool.
You guys have a whole community going on in that server, you know?
It's like a sub-community in the community.
Oh, wait a minute.
Netriok, when you play hardcore and you die, your world gets deleted though, right?
You have to start over with a new world.
That's my understanding.
Am I mistaken there?
Okay, okay.
The world is gone if you die.
Perfect.
That's what I thought.
Have you seen how long some players last in hardcore?
There are people who keep worlds for years.
I mean, I could also just make a world and log out, you know?
There it is.
Easiest game of my life.
Your girlfriend made an edited video of the event.
Oh, okay, okay.
That's awesome.
That's really cool.
Lillipad LTD.
Okay, guys, I gotta go.
I really gotta go eat some food.
It's almost 12 o'clock here and I haven't even eaten dinner.
I inhaled a couple of apples before the stream, but that's about it.
I'm actually dying.
So I know I say that every time, but yeah.
I will see you guys around.
Thank you so much for joining for this.
It's been a blast.
Next time we're gonna play some more...
What's it called?
Slay the Spire.
We're gonna slay the Spire.
Hell yeah.
And we're gonna do it.
Let's raid someone while we're here.
Someone in the same category.
Who's playing right now?
There is a third dinner.
Tactical Tailor.
Let's go for the third dinner.
I like that.
Third dinner.
First look at Noita as well.
Oh, that's awesome.
I need to watch more Let's Plays of people playing Noita after this.
I need to really...
experience what you guys are experiencing when you see me play the game, you know?
I wanna see people's reactions to all the crazy shit happening in Noita.
Alright, I'll see you around.
Have a good night.
Bye bye.